<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Chris Woodall</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in About on Chris Woodall</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 13:30:09 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MBTA-Assisted Wachusett Region Bike Overnight: Wachusett Station-Barre-Worcester</title><link>/posts/2025-05-07-wachussets-barre-worcester/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 13:30:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/2025-05-07-wachussets-barre-worcester/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="origin">Origin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/img/posts/2025-05-07-bikeovernight/image-1-all-ready.JPG" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My fiancée Emily and I have been riding our bikes more frequently this year. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a great start to my season with plenty of early days on my hardtail (Banshee Paradox) and a fun &amp;ldquo;race/ride&amp;rdquo; at the Mix Tape event in Freetown, MA. As Emily built up her own riding strength, we wanted to embark on a multi-day trip together.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in bikepacking since purchasing my Surly CrossCheck in 2018 but had never actually taken the plunge. Usually, climbing trips, work, and family obligations took precedence. This year, I decided to prioritize cycling—particularly gravel riding and mountain biking. On January 1, 2025, I committed myself by registering for the Vermont Overland Race (August) and the Mix Tape race (April). There&amp;rsquo;s only time for so many pursuits in a given year, and I prefer to immerse myself deeply in whatever I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Brief Review of My 2023 Mini-Sabbatical</title><link>/posts/2023-08-29-mini-sabbatical-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 13:30:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/2023-08-29-mini-sabbatical-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>During the summer of 2023, I took 3 months off from June to September as I transitioned between two jobs. I wanted to experiment with taking some free time to travel, move, and reconnect with my hobbies. I found this time to be very beneficial for my physical and mental health, and I am very grateful to have had the privilege to have been able to take some extended time off from work. I found some perspective and space that will serve me well in my future endeavors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>31 Climbs</title><link>/climbing/2023-04-01-31-climbs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/climbing/2023-04-01-31-climbs/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I turned 31, which is not an auspicious year; other than it being the last year that you can represent on one hand counting in binary (&lt;code>2^5-1&lt;/code>). So I went down to MetroRock in Essex, VT and spent about 5 hours in the gym getting my 31 climbs together with support from friends and loved ones. To plan I started by listing out some rules:&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- more -->
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Climb on ropes only or if doing boulders you need to link to rope length.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Climbing up and down counts as 2 pitches.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All climbing grades 5.6 and above are in&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Every 5 climbs you need to do something 5.10a or greater.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Falls are ok, but you must get to the top of the climb without cheating past moves for it to count.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You must finish the climb an uncompleted climb does not count&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Auto-belays are good to go.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No more than 4 repeats of a single route.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="/img/posts/climbing/2023-04-01-31-climbs/1.jpg" alt="">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Phoenix Project by Gene Kim, Kevin Behr and George Spafford</title><link>/reading/2022-10-09-the-phoenix-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2022-10-09-the-phoenix-project/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Phoenix-Project-DevOps-Helping-Business-ebook/dp/B078Y98RG8/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1MCS4OFYKHY7N&amp;amp;keywords=The+Phoenix+project&amp;amp;qid=1665793481&amp;amp;qu=eyJxc2MiOiIyLjA3IiwicXNhIjoiMS42NiIsInFzcCI6IjEuNzgifQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;sprefix=the+phoenix+projec%2Caps%2C93&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;ufe=app_do%3Aamzn1.fos.006c50ae-5d4c-4777-9bc0-4513d670b6bc">The Phoenix Project&lt;/a> has been recommended to me by a lot of people over the years. As a book about DevOps in an IT industry a little detached from my current work in motor controls, and software, for electric aviation, I was a little concerned that I might not find a lot that was useful for me; however, the journey &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Phoenix-Project-DevOps-Helping-Business-ebook/dp/B078Y98RG8/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1MCS4OFYKHY7N&amp;amp;keywords=The+Phoenix+project&amp;amp;qid=1665793481&amp;amp;qu=eyJxc2MiOiIyLjA3IiwicXNhIjoiMS42NiIsInFzcCI6IjEuNzgifQ%3D%3D&amp;amp;sprefix=the+phoenix+projec%2Caps%2C93&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;ufe=app_do%3Aamzn1.fos.006c50ae-5d4c-4777-9bc0-4513d670b6bc">The Phoenix Project&lt;/a> takes you on was far too familiar, and while the specific solutions might not apply the core of &lt;strong>The Three Ways&lt;/strong>, looking at engineering as plant management, and some of the realizations about how to align and work in a larger organization will certainly aid me in my career.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>To Sell Is Human by Daniel H. Pink</title><link>/reading/2022-08-24-to-sell-is-human/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2022-08-24-to-sell-is-human/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sell-Human-Surprising-Moving-Others/dp/1594631905/">To Sell Is Human&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://www.danpink.com">Daniel H. Pink&lt;/a> posits that selling is not some scummy thing car salesmen do, instead, it is a core part of being human. In the modern world, we are all salespeople of our craft, we are all engaged in non-sales selling every day: convincing our partner to go to see a specific movie, dating, and convincing our boss to give us a new project. Whatever it is we are in the role of a salesperson every day, whether we like it or not. If we are in this role why not embrace it? So what do we need to do to embrace it? We need to develop the following traits:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing an Autowah Effect in Python using PyAudio</title><link>/posts/2022-02-28-autowah/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 13:30:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022-02-28-autowah/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I started playing bass guitar and working some &lt;a href="/music">music&lt;/a> after a long period of not working on music too much. I was listening to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GNCd_ERZvZM">Them Changes&lt;/a> by Thundercat and became somewhat curious about the &amp;ldquo;wah&amp;rdquo;/envelope follower effect that he uses heavily throughout the song. This effect is pretty standard in funk, and other genres. However, I became interested in how the effect is implemented and decided to throw together an audio development environment in Python and implement this for myself. I used Python, PyAudio, NumPy and SciPy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Go to &lt;a href="https://github.com/cwoodall/py-audio-effects-autowah">github to see the code&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Git To Sync Obsidian Notes on iOS with a-shell (free)</title><link>/posts/2022-01-02-obsidian-ios-sync/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 13:30:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022-01-02-obsidian-ios-sync/</guid><description>&lt;p>Obsidian is a wonderful note-taking too, but until mid-2021 there was no official mobile application. I use git to host my Obsidian vaults, and github to store them and sometimes create websites from them using a GitHub Action, GitHub Pages and Neuron. This is how I host my &lt;a href="https://cwoodall.com/generative-art-studio/">Generative Art Studio&lt;/a> page. However, on iOS there is no native support for using git to sync your notes. You can use iCloud, or Obsidian Sync. I have no issues with paying for either of these services, but I wanted to be able to keep my current workflow, but extend it to mobile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I developed a free method using &lt;a href="https://holzschu.github.io/a-Shell_iOS">&lt;strong>a-shell&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, which can be automated, after initial setup, using iOS Shortcuts. There are two other methods that are well documented on the &lt;a href="https://forum.obsidian.md">Obsidian forum&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://forum.obsidian.md/t/mobile-setting-up-ios-git-based-syncing-with-mobile-app-using-working-copy/16499">WorkingCopy&lt;/a>: WorkingCopy is a paid application, which runs&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://forum.obsidian.md/t/mobile-sync-with-git-on-ios-for-free-using-ish/20861/8">iSH&lt;/a>: iSH runs an alpine linux container, and this method works. However, it does not have shortcut access, so you would need to launch the application and run git manually.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This method uses &lt;a href="https://holzschu.github.io/a-Shell_iOS">&lt;strong>a-shell&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>, which uses webAssembly for many of it&amp;rsquo;s executables, which allows it to be more flexible, this has support for python, lua, javascript, C and C++, and most importantly git, using lg2. The main benefit is it is free (iSH is also free), and it is natively scriptable using Shortcuts (which iSH is not).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>January 2022</title><link>/now/2022-01-02/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 12:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>/now/2022-01-02/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-am-i-doing-now">What am I doing &lt;em>now&lt;/em>?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Preparing for a new year with a concentration on my mental and physical health, building community, and improving my communication skills.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Working on chord melodies for Autumn Leaves, All of Me, and whatever else strikes my fancy on Mandolin.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Playing around with embedded test automation using my Rigol Scope&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting back into skiing, ice climbing, and rock climbing in the gym.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>More motors!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="my-priorities-are">My priorities are:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Cultivating a meditation, fitness and journaling practice.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Making music, and art.
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/temporalshift/knight-of-infinite-resignation?si=9264a4b9843f4857aa3779a46c7ec55f&amp;amp;utm_source=clipboard&amp;amp;utm_medium=text&amp;amp;utm_campaign=social_sharing">Knight of Inifinite Resignation&lt;/a> is one of my first new pieces in a while.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="quotes-on-my-mind">Quotes On My Mind&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Life before Death
Strength before Weakness
Journey before Destination&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>July 2021</title><link>/now/2021-07-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 12:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>/now/2021-07-18/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-am-i-doing-now">What am I doing &lt;em>now&lt;/em>?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Working on electric aircraft at &lt;a href="beta.team">BETA Technologies&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continuing to love &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian.md&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Working on &lt;a href="https://cwoodall.com/generative-art-studio">generative art&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Taking notes using &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian&lt;/a>, generating art using &lt;a href="https://kotlinlang.org/">Kotlin&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://guide.openrndr.org/#/">OpenRNDR&lt;/a>, and publishing using &lt;a href="https://neuron.zettel.page/">neuron&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting more into mountain biking&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preparing to run a 8k in August and a half-marathon in October&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Preparing for 2 weeks in the PNW in September&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Motor Controls!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="my-priorities-are">My priorities are:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Building strong habits around going getting enough sleep, improved health and improved sleep&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting a personal task management solution that works for me in place&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="quotes-on-my-mind">Quotes On My Mind&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The Buddha told his disciples, “Believe nothing, no matter where you read it, or who said it, no matter if I have said it, unless it agrees with your own reason and your own common sense.” I say the same to you—you must assume the responsibility for what you believe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automating Musescore 3.6 PDF and MP3 Generation Using Github Actions</title><link>/posts/2021-03-28-musescore-3.6-github-action/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 15:30:09 -0400</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-03-28-musescore-3.6-github-action/</guid><description>&lt;p>Back in the day, I used to use &lt;a href="https://www.avid.com/sibelius">Sibelius&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.finalemusic.com/">Finale&lt;/a> for music composition, and engraving. &lt;a href="https://musescore.org">MuseScore 3.6&lt;/a> is an open-source, cross-platform music composition tool that fits right in there with the other two. Considering that it is free it punches above its weight class. I first found out about MuseScore when I watched a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4hZxo96x48A">review of its interface by Tantacrul&lt;/a> who ripped the UI to shreds. I thought that this would be the end of it for me, however, I later found out that after this video was made Tantacrul joined the MuseScore team as a project manager on the UI team, and with 3.6 it seems like they have already started to fix a lot of the underlying issues (and I found it to be a joy to work in).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Link Your Turns</title><link>/posts/2021-03-02-link-your-turns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 21:20:47 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-03-02-link-your-turns/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I am skiing and I am in a flow state I tend to be able to make all the turns I need to to keep my speed under control, weave through trees and not get flung down a steep mogul field. However, when I am not fully present I will tend to overturn. I can&amp;rsquo;t link my turns. The anxiety, fear, lack of concentration comes over and under the worst conditions I can end up going backwards down hill. Skiing, and mountain biking, are pretty good analogies for decision making under pressure. They are flow-dependent sports, you need the fitness and skill to get there, but you also need the whole body focus that is synonymous with a flow state. In my experience it would appear that high performers in many fields are making decisions and corrections rapidly: balancing speed, control and enjoyment as they find their line down the mountain. They keep linking their turns.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Meditation Notes and Resources</title><link>/posts/2021-01-30-meditation-notes-and-resources/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 19:36:34 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-01-30-meditation-notes-and-resources/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the past year or so I got a few people asking me about meditation and &lt;a href="https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/basics/mindfulness">mindfulness&lt;/a> practice and how I would recommend getting started. I am not an expert, monk, or any sort of authority on the subject. I am a beginner, and sometimes a little too proud of my progress. Right now I feel the need to reflect on this information I have gathered, and consolidate some of the texts, advice, and thoughts that I have expressed personally. I do this with the hope it may help others, but also may help myself recognize some of the gems in my practice and revisit them with more vigor, and awareness.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>January 2021</title><link>/now/2021-01-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 12:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>/now/2021-01-01/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-am-i-doing-now">What am I doing &lt;em>now&lt;/em>?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Working on electric aircraft at &lt;a href="beta.team">BETA Technologies&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Skiing!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Playing around with note taking in &lt;a href="https://obsidian.md/">Obsidian.md&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learning a little &lt;a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/">Rust&lt;/a> each day.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="my-priorities-are">My priorities are:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Building strong habits around going to sleep, waking up, doing deep work, and building new skills&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="quotes-on-my-mind">Quotes On My Mind&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Only ideas won by walking have any value&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; &lt;a href="https://fs.blog/2014/05/a-philosophy-of-walking/">Friedrich Nietzsche&lt;/a>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Forty hour workweeks are a relic of the Industrial Age. Knowledge workers function like athletes — train and sprint, then rest and reassess.
&amp;ndash; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/naval/status/873624849230385152?lang=en">Naval Ravikant&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jump Rope with Abstractions</title><link>/posts/2020-12-30-jump-rope-with-abstractions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 08:37:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/2020-12-30-jump-rope-with-abstractions/</guid><description>&lt;p>One skill I attempt to practice consistently is the ability to jump through levels of abstraction. This requires having a growing toolkit of
abstractions, such as some of those in Shane Parish from Farnam Street&amp;rsquo;s series on &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Great-Mental-Models-Thinking-Concepts/dp/1999449002/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;hvadid=77790577707398&amp;amp;hvbmt=be&amp;amp;hvdev=c&amp;amp;hvqmt=e&amp;amp;keywords=farnam+street+mental+models&amp;amp;qid=1609377528&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;tag=mh0b-20">The Great Mental Models&lt;/a>. It also
requires being able to have emotional awareness and detachment to abandon ways of thinking and move on to more suitable ones. This is a
meta-skill that can make life better.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>November 2020</title><link>/now/2020-11-28/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 12:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>/now/2020-11-28/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-am-i-doing-now">What am I doing &lt;em>now&lt;/em>?&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Working at &lt;a href="beta.team">BETA Technologies&lt;/a> on electric aviation, still working on electric propulsion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I have been playing mandolin regularly, and making improvements slowly&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting ready for ski and ice season, by climbing at the gym more.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="my-priorities-are">My priorities are:&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Deepening and continuing my practice of Buddhism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Treating my body well by exercising and eating nourishing foods&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Continuing to develop expertise in motor controls.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="quotes-on-my-mind">Quotes On My Mind&lt;/h3>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Simply begin again&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is The Output Of Your Work?</title><link>/posts/2020-11-27-output-of-your-work/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 17:44:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/2020-11-27-output-of-your-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few years ago, while in the middle of a big product release, I turned to a co-worker and asked them:
&lt;strong>What is the output of your work?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This sounds like a silly question, but I found it to be enlightening to reflect on. Here we were, stressed out about
making something. However, what we were really doing was producing the documentation, the knowledge, and the confidence
in the product we were making. It is easy to get lost in the idea that what you produce is the
gizmo, gadget, or the most tactile result of your actions. In some ways it is tempting to think that if you paint you produce a
painting; if you write music you produce a song; if you write code it is the website or demo that is the output of your work.
On reflection I found that while the direct goal is often one output of your work, in many ways is more a side-effect.
In this view the main output is the information, experience, and documentation that is created by the process of doing the work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Recursion by Blake Crouch</title><link>/reading/2020-02-14-recursion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2020-02-14-recursion/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B07HDSHP7N/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1">Recursion&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://blakecrouch.com/">Blake Crouch&lt;/a> is an interesting take on a time travel thriller, involving characters and relationships across multiple time lines.
It is interesting how some of the characters who at first seem minor become integral parts of the story, developing into more interesting and
intelligent characters over their recursions, creating small perturbations leading to different lives, but infrequently to different outcomes.
What does it mean to try to change the present by going into the past? Especially when everyone immediately recollects all relevant timelines
once the moment the timelines diverged occurs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>February 2020</title><link>/now/2020-02-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/now/2020-02-01/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-am-i-doing-now">What am I doing &lt;em>now&lt;/em>?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Reflecting on 2019, it was a crazy year with a lot to learn on a personal level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am now in Burlington, VT working at BETA Technologies on the future of electric aviation! My main focus is on inverters for controlling motors. This is taking up most of my time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been meditating daily (using a combination of Unified Mindfulness and Sam Harris&amp;rsquo; Waking Up app), trying to do daily creative acts (water colors, music, programming, etc), and when I can going to yoga. Climbing has taken a little bit of a back seat at the moment, but I want to set some good goals to drive forward my climbing performance. I have realized how deep and meaningful climbing is to me. One of my biggest goals right now is preparing for a 10 day mediation retreat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fear and Trembling by Kierkegaard</title><link>/reading/2018-11-01-fear-and-trembling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-11-01-fear-and-trembling/</guid><description/></item><item><title>21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari</title><link>/reading/2018-10-28-21-lessons-for-the-21st-century/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-10-28-21-lessons-for-the-21st-century/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Myth of Sisyphus by Camus</title><link>/reading/2018-09-23-myth-of-sisyphus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-09-23-myth-of-sisyphus/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Apology by Plato</title><link>/reading/2018-08-13-apology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-08-13-apology/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Crux by Ramez Naam</title><link>/reading/2018-07-30-the-crux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-07-30-the-crux/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Espresso Lessons by Arno Ilgner</title><link>/reading/2018-07-11-espresso-lessons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-07-11-espresso-lessons/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Roadside Picnic by Arkady and Boris Strugatsky</title><link>/reading/2018-07-02-roadside-picnic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-07-02-roadside-picnic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Miracle of Mindfulness by Thich Nhat Hahn</title><link>/reading/2018-06-23-the-miracle-of-mindfulness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-06-23-the-miracle-of-mindfulness/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Desert Solitaire by Edward Abbey</title><link>/reading/2018-06-07-desert-solitaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-06-07-desert-solitaire/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Wandering Earth by Cixin Liu</title><link>/reading/2018-04-17-the-wandering-earth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-04-17-the-wandering-earth/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dharma Bums by Jack Kerouac</title><link>/reading/2018-03-18-dharma-bums/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-03-18-dharma-bums/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mt. Avalon Trip Report</title><link>/climbing/2018-03-13-mt-avalon-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/climbing/2018-03-13-mt-avalon-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>On Saturday March 10, 2018 Don, Toni and I ventured out to &lt;a href="https://www.mountainproject.com/area/107472592/mt-avalon">Mt. Avalon&lt;/a>. With the &lt;a href="http://neclimbs.com">NEClimbs Ice Report&lt;/a>
looking rather pessimistic we deiced to go somewhere with no reported ice condition information. I figured the less we
knew about the ice the better off we were. So we woke up bright and early, got ourselves some food at Patches and then
leisurely waited for Bear Notch Ski and Snowshoe Rentals to open so we could rent ourselves a pair of snowshoes for our
little bushwack.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Climb Strong by Steve Betchel</title><link>/reading/2018-03-07-climb-strong/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-03-07-climb-strong/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Reflection in C++ to Generate Serializable Structs Using libclang and Python</title><link>/posts/2018-02-24-using-clang-and-python-to-generate-cpp-struct-serde-fns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 17:44:16 -0500</pubDate><guid>/posts/2018-02-24-using-clang-and-python-to-generate-cpp-struct-serde-fns/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have recently found myself writing a bunch of serialization (and
deserialization) functions in C++ for some very basic structs, and
classes. Each of these serialization functions has the same basic
form which is basically a series of function calls to convert
some data of some type into it&amp;rsquo;s msgpack representation. As the
number of structs grows this becomes tedious and hard to upgrade. Also,
there are a few points where programmer error can result in major hard
to detect problems, if the ordering is wrong, or the number of fields
is wrong, then all bets are off. I will be the first to admit that
Google Protobufs basically solves this problem entirely by describing
the transfer messages, and datatypes in its own language and then
compiling the target representation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Inspired by my recent usage of &lt;a href="https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/">rust&lt;/a> I decided to see if I could create
the equivalent of rust&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>#[derive()]&lt;/code> syntax for applying procedural
macros to a struct. You can see my experiment on &lt;a href="https://github.com/cwoodall/cpp-serde-gen">github&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gear Review: Anker Ice Screw Holder</title><link>/climbing/2018-02-06-gear-review-anker-ice-screw-holder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/climbing/2018-02-06-gear-review-anker-ice-screw-holder/</guid><description>&lt;p>I just got myself the Anker Equipment screw holder for my brand new rack of ice screws. This thing was $45.00 and holds
12 screws. It even has a little pouch in the middle which can fit a 10cm screw, or file depending on what you want to use it for.
Generally speaking I found it to be rather compact compared to the BD offering. It fits 12 screws nicely and folds up to a rather compact size.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Squamish Trip Report</title><link>/climbing/2018-02-19-squamish-trip-report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/climbing/2018-02-19-squamish-trip-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>This summer I went to Squamish from August 11th-18th, 2017 with Alice Chiang, and a group made up of Matt, Lauren, Tiff and Josh. I climbed with Alice throughout the trip and had an awesome time on the splitter and reasonably high-friction granite found at Squamish. I had been once before on 2016 and had an objective in mind I had recruited Alice for: an ascent of the first peak of the Chief via &lt;a href="https://www.mountainproject.com/route/106495528/calculus-crack">Calculus Crack&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.mountainproject.com/route/106864599/the-squamish-butt-face">Squamish Butt Face&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Rock Climbers Training Manual by Mark L. Anderson and Michael L. Anderson</title><link>/reading/2018-01-03-rock-climbers-training-manual/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-01-03-rock-climbers-training-manual/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mistborn: The Final Empire (Book 1) by Brandon Sanderson</title><link>/reading/2017-12-30-mistborn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-12-30-mistborn/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few of my friends have been trying to get me to read a book by &lt;a href="https://brandonsanderson.com/">Brandon Sanderson&lt;/a> for quite some time. Given that I enjoyed Rothfuss&amp;rsquo; &lt;em>Name of the Wind&lt;/em>, and Lynch&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>The Lies of Locke Lamora&lt;/em> I thought a good starting place would be &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Mistborn-Final-Empire-Brandon-Sanderson-ebook/dp/B002GYI9C4/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1515100855&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=mistborn">Mistborn: The Final Empire&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, which have a similar setup. The best thing about Mistborn is the world it is set in, and the fascinating and engaging pace with which new details are introduced about the world, characters and magic systems. There are at least two magic systems in Mistborn, Allomancy and Feruchemy, and both of them use metals as their medium of use. The thing I love about this magic system is that it has strict limitations which are easy to think about. Allomancy consumes metals, which means there is a natural resource management problem; where Feruchemy uses metals as a storage medium, which means that it can only store and release what the user puts into it (with some loss based on the rate of use). I also loved the character of Vin, and the overall heist like nature of the story. It is very engaging and I would recommend it to any lover of fantasy novels (and magic systems).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Odyssey by Homer (Translated by Richard Fagles)</title><link>/reading/2017-12-13-the-odyssey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-12-13-the-odyssey/</guid><description>&lt;p>Homer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Odyssey-Penguin-Classics-Deluxe-ebook/dp/B000OCXGRS/ref=pd_sim_351_3?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=XQXQJ1R75XY2475HPFRW">The Odyssey&lt;/a>&lt;/em>, as translated by Richard Fagles, is a classic. The Fagles translation reads very naturally to a native English speaker. While I am sure there are some trade-offs when compared to a more literal translation, I felt that this translation was very enjoyable. I read this epic because it is a foundational text of the western literary tradition, and it really shows in it&amp;rsquo;s influence on other works. The form, the characters, and the motivations are all so familiar even though the original story is from so long go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Graveyard Book by Neil Gaiman</title><link>/reading/2017-11-22-graveyard-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-11-22-graveyard-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started listening to &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0011UJM48">The Graveyard Book&lt;/a>&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="http://www.neilgaiman.com/">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a> while I was in JFK airport in NY.
I had missed a connecting flight and was alone in the airport for those early morning hours where
the bustling of the airport stops. The ambiance of the airport fit the tone of the book. I really
enjoyed the story-telling. Part of it was that the Audible full-cast production was very well
done and the writing style fits an audiobook. Each chapter is a story in and of itself, and the
book follows Nobody, a boy who is being brought up by ghosts in a graveyard. He learns things
which are not typical, but through this he is able to overcome the challenges which prevent him
from living a normal life. It is a beautiful coming of age story, and touches not just on the
heroic, but also some of the ambiguity and evil which is inherent in living a life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I Manage My Reading List With Trello</title><link>/posts/2017-10-16-how-i-manage-my-reading-list-with-trello/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2017-10-16-how-i-manage-my-reading-list-with-trello/</guid><description>&lt;p>In college I frequently would go on book reading binges during breaks, but I could not keep
myself to a consistent schedule to read for pleasure during classes. This &amp;ldquo;not enough
time&amp;rdquo; syndrome carried over to after I left college, even though I was not actually
particularly busy outside of work. Missing reading I started to gather books I wanted
to read, but was having trouble keeping track of all of them, and sorting through what
to read next. So I gave some reason to the madness by using
&lt;a href="http://trello.com">Trello&lt;/a>. You can view my
&lt;a href="https://trello.com/b/9l0rYMxD/reading-list">Trello Reading List&lt;/a> and see what I
have on there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fundamentally by maintaining a list which is so flexible and easy to manipulate I
have added some tangibility to the abstract concept of &amp;ldquo;books I want to read&amp;rdquo;. I
can also track and set goals related to reading rate and diversity of books since
I maintain all of that data. Another plus is that it makes it easy to track what
I need to write blurbs for my website. Some of my friends use other systems,
including &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/">goodreads&lt;/a> and just maintaining a literal
(and literary) stack of books. I like the Trello system because it felt easier to
abandon my reading past, than it did on goodreads, which made it feel like I should
log every book I have read since birth. That said the friends I have who use
goodreads seem to like it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read on for more information on how I organize my Trello reading list.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Weather Makers by Tim Flannery</title><link>/reading/2017-10-10-weather-makers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-10-10-weather-makers/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B008RZKO6A">The Weather Makers&lt;/a>&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="http://www.timflannery.com/">Tim Flannery&lt;/a> is a frightening and enlightening book about global warming. Though it is about 10 years old at this point it had a few major points:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The evidence for human linked global warming is very strong (and has only become stronger)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The reduction in biodiversity is intense, and probably irreversible; we have changed climates and biomes and there is probably no going back.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There is no silver bullet, we need all nations to collaborate and the issues are largely policy issues. However, individual contributions are larger than I thought and in aggregate can improve the situation dramatically. These issues can be made easier with appropriate application of technology (electric cars, solar panels, etc.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A benefit of a green energy economy is that it can wrestle the production of power from corporations to communities, through town owned infrastructure (wind), and personal ownership (solar).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Coal is the enemy, other forms of carbon emissions are more efficient and thus slightly less problematic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>There is some hope&amp;hellip;&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I need to continue studying these issues, I think it can make a major impact on my habits and push me to try to get more involved.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Wizard of Earthsea by Ursula K. Le Guin</title><link>/reading/2017-10-09-a-wizard-of-earthsea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-10-09-a-wizard-of-earthsea/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Wizard-Earthsea-Cycle/dp/0547773749/ref=asap_bc?ie=UTF8">A Wizard of Earthsea&lt;/a>&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="http://www.ursulakleguin.com/">Ursula K. Le Guin&lt;/a> is a fun fantasy novel aimed at young adults and teens. It
follows a wizard named Ged/Sparrowhawk as he tries to get rid of an evil he brought into the world through
his own arrogance. It is well written and enjoyable, like &lt;em>Left Hand of Darkness&lt;/em> the world building is
superb and is given to you in little shards as you need to know about it. The lessons of the book are deep
and there is a lot to learn from the character development of Ged, as he learns to be more humble and to
live life rather than run from death.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Left Hand of Darkness by Ursula K. Le Guin</title><link>/reading/2017-09-30-left-hand-of-darkness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-09-30-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid><description>&lt;p>What would it be like on a world where everyone was an asexual hermaphrodite
99% of the time? Where gender and sex were not the primary focus of day to
day life, because most of the time everyone was the same in this regard?
&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00YBA7PGW/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1">Left Hand of Darkness&lt;/a>&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="http://www.ursulakleguin.com/">Ursula K. Le Guin&lt;/a> thrusts Genly Ai, a
run of the mill male Terran human, into the middle of the planet
Winter where the inhabitants fit this description. His mission is to
convince them to join the rest of humanity in a share of information. This book
really plays with the idea of what it means to be human, and the role of
gender and sex within that. It tries to tease out those things which may be
constant, and those things which are due to a duality which has been baked
into our culture. Le Guin also does a great job at world building without it
feeling false, and just tying all of the characters together. It is an
excellent book with an excellent moral.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nexus by Ramez Naam</title><link>/reading/2017-08-20-nexus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-08-20-nexus/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00TOZI7FM/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1">Nexus&lt;/a>&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="http://rameznaam.com/">Ramez Naam&lt;/a> is a science fiction book which takes place in the near
future, where technology has been created to link human minds, and possibly
control them. Naam inspects different social impacts of these technologies
ranging from the most profound and inspirational uses (such as building new
levels of empath and human connection) to the most disturbing and dark abuses
(such as making it trivial to coerce people). The technology seems and feels
plausible throughout the novel, besides towards the end where a few flimsy
cyberpunk-esque plot devices are used to move the story forward. I also enjoyed
the inspection of the technology through different lenses, such as, a Buddhist
perspective in addition to a Silicon Valley hot shot perspective.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dune by Frank Herbert</title><link>/reading/2017-07-27-dune/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-07-27-dune/</guid><description>&lt;p>I finally read &lt;a href="http://www.dunenovels.com/author/frank-herbert">Frank Herbert&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s classic novel &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Dune-Frank-Herbert-ebook/dp/B00B7NPRY8/ref=asap_bc?ie=UTF8">Dune&lt;/a>&lt;/em> after avoiding it for a
long time. My father gave me a copy after finishing the [Lord of the
Rings] during middle-school. At the time I found the book to be slow
and overly political, but I came back to it at the perfect time.
The world rife with political unrest and I am more capable of dealing the
the moral ambiguity of the work. I am also more excited by the ecological and
social phenomenon of the Freemen and Spice. This book has been discussed many
times before; however, here are a few major take aways:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Beyond The Vertical by Layton Kor</title><link>/reading/2017-06-26-beyond-the-vertical/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-06-26-beyond-the-vertical/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Beyond-Vertical-Layton-Kor/dp/0762781394">Beyond The Vertical&lt;/a>&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Layton_Kor">Layton Kor&lt;/a> follows the climbing career from
childhood into old age of the author. The format of the book is a series of
short vignettes of different climbing trips from a wide variety of Layton&amp;rsquo;s
partners (including Steve Roper, Jim McCarthy and Royal Robbins) glued
together by Layton&amp;rsquo;s own recounting of his climbing career.
The descriptions of their approach to climbing, and the shear sense of adventure
that compelled them inspires me as a human and as a climber. Layton&amp;rsquo;s major
contributions were to Colorado climbing at Eldorado Canyon, Long&amp;rsquo;s Peak and
The Black Canyon of the Gunnison. He also put up bold climbs in Yosemite,
the Dolomites and elsewhere making himself into a climbing legend.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sapiens by Yuval Noah Harari</title><link>/reading/2017-06-14-sapiens/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-06-14-sapiens/</guid><description>&lt;p>Humans are story-tellers, we communicated by telling others about our
experiences, about those of others, and most interestingly about things
that never even happened. These stories create a shared network of
knowledge and information, which allow us to cooperate and form networks
of trust, and eventually layer on top of each other to form concepts like
money, religion and the nation-state. &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.ynharari.com/">Sapiens&lt;/a>&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Sapiens-Humankind-Yuval-Noah-Harari-ebook/dp/B00ICN066A/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1507586266&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=Sapiens">Yuval Noah Harari&lt;/a>
explores and reveals pieces of the story telling nature of humanity and
reveals the good and the bad of this. On one hand it is how we are able
to cooperate and solve some big world problems; but on the other hand it
is the reason we have those problems and why we can execute large
displays of evil and inhumanity. &lt;em>&lt;a href="http://www.ynharari.com/">Sapiens&lt;/a>&lt;/em> really is a book that makes
you see the world in a different way and also it helped me deal with
some of the shared human delusions like money. Just because it is a
delusion doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it any less real, humans use these abstract ideas
to form a basis of how they should interact and thus makes them necessary
parts of our life. They may be more fluid than the laws of physics, but
they are in many ways no less important.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tribe by Sebastian Junger</title><link>/reading/2017-05-02-tribe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-05-02-tribe/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.sebastianjunger.com">Sebastian Junger&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B01BCJDSNI/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1">Tribe&lt;/a>&lt;/em> is a short but poignant book about the transition
from childhood to adulthood and belonging. The book seems to focus on a male
perspective, but is not exclusionary so much as just very specific. The focus is
on how do humans adapt from being part of groups—such as the military, where
they have a strong sense of belonging, purpose and brotherhood—to being
single independent units which are so common in modern America. It really delves
into the psychological pain that is created by our current social structures, and
how they are different in some other cultures. For me one of the most
interesting examples was related to veterans in America versus veterans in
Israel. In the US veterans are treated as outsiders, as people who did &amp;ldquo;great&amp;rdquo; things, but whose experiences could infect the population. As a result they do not feel welcome and can become isolated, creating symptoms of psychological diseases like PTSD, or making them worse. In Israel (according to Junger), since
the battlefront, and soldiers are so close all the time the experience of being a
soldier is a bonding experience to the nation, not an isolating one. Thus the
soldiers tend to fit back into society. I thought this idea was interesting, and
it seems to apply to any kind of negativity in America, it infects you&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Barbarian Days: A Surfing Life by William Finnegan</title><link>/reading/2017-04-27-barbarian-days/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-04-27-barbarian-days/</guid><description>&lt;p>[William Finnegan&amp;rsquo;s] book &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B00G3L6JMS/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1">Barbarian Days: A Surfing Life&lt;/a>&lt;/em> follows the
authors obsession with surfing, from his childhood to adulthood with a
long section of being a surf bum in between. I have never surfed, but I
found myself being dragged into the lingo and culture and really yearning
in a way for that open life adventure. For me climbing fits a similar role
in my life, I know to some degree it is pointless, yet I come back to it and
it keeps providing something for me. This is Finnegan&amp;rsquo;s well of inspiration,
even at those periods where he leaves the sport, and each time he comes back
it brings him something new.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hard-Boiled Wonderland and the End of The World by Haruki Murakami</title><link>/reading/2017-03-29-hard-boiled-wonderland-end-of-the-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-03-29-hard-boiled-wonderland-end-of-the-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hard-Boiled-Wonderland-World-Vintage-International-ebook/dp/B004AP9W1O/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1509327045&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=hard+boiled+wonderland+and+the+end+of+the+world">Hard-Boiled Wonderland and the End of The World&lt;/a>&lt;/em> by &lt;a href="http://www.harukimurakami.com/">Haruki Murakami&lt;/a>
involves 2 parallel, seemingly unrelated stories, which become more and more
intertwined as the stories develop. One of them takes place in a cyberpunk
like future, with humans who act as encryption/decryption services, and the
other in a surreal fantasy land where your shadow is removed from you and
you can&amp;rsquo;t leave. The story is intriguing and I can&amp;rsquo;t discuss it much more
without spoiling, but I found it to be thought provoking and it was a
little bit of a smoother read than other Murakami books, but still had all
of the beautiful and delicate language which Murakami does so well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Kafka on the Shore by Haruki Murakami</title><link>/reading/2017-03-09-kafka-on-the-shore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-03-09-kafka-on-the-shore/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.harukimurakami.com/">Haruki Murakami&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B000FC2ROU/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1">Kafka on the Shore&lt;/a>&lt;/em> is an elegantly written book
filled with heady references and a magical-realism which penetrates this
abstract reinterpretation of Oedipus Rex. The setting is outstanding,
describing not just Japan, but all of the subtly magical pieces of the
world. The spiritual becomes an integral part of the novel, and nothing
is literal. It stretches your mind as a seemingly direct prophecy is
carried out through the most abstract and dream-like of means. There
is a lot of really hard to handle content, as the main
character develops and is not always the best person. However, he seems
to learn who he is, and a bit of empathy by the end as the hero&amp;rsquo;s
journey comes to a close. Well written and worth it, but it can be a
little dense at times, which I enjoyed but others might not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Good Omens by Terry Pratchett and Neil Gaiman</title><link>/reading/2017-03-06-good-omens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-03-06-good-omens/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0054LJGWS/ref=dp-kindle-redirect?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;btkr=1">Good Omens&lt;/a>&lt;/em> is a collaboration between &lt;a href="https://www.terrypratchettbooks.com/">Terry Pratchett&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.neilgaiman.com/">Neil Gaiman&lt;/a>
which I listened to as an audiobook. A humorous, satirical and biting novel
about the apocalypse, starring a demon who is not so bad, an angel who is not
so good, and an anti-christ who just wants to play with his friends. I found it
to be hilarious, with a lot of funny social and religious commentary. The book
feels mostly like Terry Pratchett, with a little bit of the unique darkness Neil
Gaiman brings; however, I think the collaboration was very successful. While
Pratchett&amp;rsquo;s voice overpowers Neil&amp;rsquo;s, the real benefit seems to have been Gaiman
feeling more comfortable writing books.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Norse Mythology by Neil Gaiman</title><link>/reading/2017-02-26-norse-mythology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-02-26-norse-mythology/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.neilgaiman.com/">Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2l9kn1i">Norse Mythology&lt;/a> is retelling of
the myths of the Norse God&amp;rsquo;s focusing mainly on: Thor, Loki, Odin, Freya
and Frey. I listend to the audiobook, narrated by Neil Gaiman, which I
thought was well done, and felt personal. The stories are engaging
and well told. The book approaches the perfect
blend of myth and narrative, and it extends from being a creative work
in its own right. The myths are accessible, but still they leave a
strong impression, and a strong curiosity to learn more about the bizarre
world of the Norse gods, and their massive flaws. I highly reccomend
reading this to anyone who liked &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2lR7Eih">American God&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a>, since
it indirectly fleshes out of the characters in that book (who are
themselves based on Norse myth).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Breakfast of Champions by Kurt Vonnegut</title><link>/reading/2017-02-13-breakfast-of-champions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-02-13-breakfast-of-champions/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my second time reading &lt;a href="https://www.vonnegut.com/">Kurt Vonnegut&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2lTZ4Os">&lt;em>Breakfast of Champions&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. When I first read this book I
appreciated the appreciated the dark sarcasm, humor and absurdism, but
I never appreciated what they were doing. This is a book written by
an author to himself as a deeply introspective work about his own
creativity. A world created to make vulnerable the author himself, to
insect life and use a work of fiction to explain itself. The characters
are setup to collide, but for no real reason or purpose, like life
itself. There was a quote from this book I read which made me wanted to
read it again, where Kilgore Trout (a character who resembles Vonnegut)
contemplates the seriousness of life with a bus driver:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Death's End by Cixin Liu</title><link>/reading/2017-02-02-deaths-end/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-02-02-deaths-end/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liu_Cixin">Cixin Liu&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> last book in the &lt;em>Three Body Problem&lt;/em> trilogy, &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2kXNeoJ">&lt;em>Death&amp;rsquo;s End&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, is a break in format from the last two books in the series. It starts before the first book and ends
millions (or possibly billions) of years afterwards following the life of Cheng Xin, a aerospace engineer who ends up making some of the most important decisions for humanity. Where the last two books are rather focused in scope this book has the feel of Isaac Asimov, or Arthur C. Clarke, and inspects human societies evolution, as well as, questions the fundamental structure of the universe. The book naturally follows the Dark Forest hypothesis to its dark but logical conclusion: as intelligent beings spread throughout space and came in contact with eachother, large intergalactic wars started taking place. In these wars the god-like aliens wielded the laws of the universe against eachother, changing universal constants and fundamentals of the galaxy, to the point where the universe itself was at risk of dying. The Darwinian need for purpetual survival of your kind leads, inveitably to death no matter the mess you make trying to avoid it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making GIFs From Videos in Linux</title><link>/posts/2016-12-24-making-gifs-from-videos-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 18:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-12-24-making-gifs-from-videos-in-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started making some &lt;code>.gif&lt;/code>s to embed in documentation and my notes as I
develop &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://github.com/cwoodall/rusty-nail">Rusty Nail&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>. I always have to lookup how to
convert the images to &lt;code>gif&lt;/code>s. Every time I am also concerned with how big the
&lt;code>.gif&lt;/code>s are so after doing some looking around I made a little script which
uses &lt;code>ffmpeg&lt;/code>, &lt;code>convert&lt;/code>, and &lt;code>gifsicle&lt;/code> (with &lt;code>giflossy&lt;/code>) to take an input
&lt;code>mp4&lt;/code>, &lt;code>webm&lt;/code>, or any video that ffmpeg can decode.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The process is this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;code>ffmpeg&lt;/code> splits the video into a directory of &lt;code>gif&lt;/code>s&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>convert&lt;/code> those images and stitches them together into one &lt;code>gif&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>gifsicle&lt;/code> optimizes the &lt;code>gif&lt;/code> and allow a stage to resize it and also change
the color. The &lt;code>giflossy&lt;/code> plug-in also can apply lossy compression to the
gif video during the optimization step.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Read on for the script.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My New Bash Prompt: Exit Codes, Unicode and Git Branches</title><link>/posts/2016-12-19-my-new-bash-prompt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-12-19-my-new-bash-prompt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I decided to customize my bash prompt. I initially started off with
the following requirements:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>It should be two lines! I have found that having the input and my prompt on
one line is not enough space most of the time.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to see my current git branch, and also if there are any uncommitted
changes in the current branch.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to see my username, host name and current directory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The current directory should be truncated so that it shows the 4 closest
directories in the path.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The status if the previous command should be show in some way.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>After some work I came up with the prompt shown above. I am excited to keep
using it and customizing it, I am also happy that I decided to use unicode in
the prompt. I have been avoiding unicode in general, but
&lt;a href="http://www.rustlang.com">Rust&lt;/a> has convinced me that I should try to accept
unicode into my life more readily!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After going through the process, here are sometake aways:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;code>printf&lt;/code> supports unicode more reliably than echo. I had some trouble
getting echo to do what I want to do&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I always forget this one. Bash functions are never what I think they are.
They are scripts you can define inside of a script. I
always seem to find this causing problems for me.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I hope you enjoy! Below is the code for my prompt! Put it into you
&lt;code>.profile&lt;/code>, &lt;code>.bash_profile&lt;/code> or &lt;code>.bashrc&lt;/code> file depending on your preference. If
you want to use it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Thoughts On the Coursera Machine Learning Course</title><link>/posts/2016-12-18-thoughts-on-coursera-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-12-18-thoughts-on-coursera-machine-learning/</guid><description>&lt;p>I completed my first &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera&lt;/a> course, which was
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning">Machine Learning&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; with &lt;a href="http://www.andrewng.org/">Andrew Ng&lt;/a> from
&lt;a href="https://www.stanford.edu/">Stanford University&lt;/a>. The course was well
taught and concentrates on building a solid base for applying
Machine Learning to a variety of problems. Andrew Ng uses examples
motivated by real-world problems to show how you might apply the algorithms
taught. I highly recommend the course if you are looking to take a MOOC and have
an interest in machine learning. I learnt a lot, but still need to apply the
knowledge in some personal projects of mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read on for more thoughts on the course and tips on how to succeed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Installing libsvm For Use With GNU Octave In Ubuntu 14.04</title><link>/posts/2016-11-19-installing-libsvm-for-octave-in-ubuntu-14-04/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-11-19-installing-libsvm-for-octave-in-ubuntu-14-04/</guid><description>&lt;p>For week 7 of the &lt;a href="http://coursera.com/">Coursera&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning/home">Machine Learning&lt;/a> course we
learned about &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Support_vector_machine">Support Vector Machines (SVM)&lt;/a>. SVMs are a useful and
powerful tools for solving classification problems. They can be tailored to
solve complicated classification boundaries, and don&amp;rsquo;t suffer from some of the
down sides of optimizing &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network">neural networks&lt;/a>. One of the
example problems uses an SVM to classify spam emails. A SVM implementation
written in MATLAB/Octave is used, but for further work &lt;a href="http://www.csie.ntu.edu.tw/~cjlin/libsvm/">libsvm&lt;/a> (or
another SVM library) is recommended. To get &lt;code>libsvm&lt;/code> working with Octave in
Ubuntu 14.04 there are a few steps that are not obvious. I did not find very
many instructions so I compiled the steps I followed to get a stable Octave
environment with &lt;code>libsvm&lt;/code>. Read on for details.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lies of Locke Lamora by Scott Lynch</title><link>/reading/2016-11-11-lies-of-locke-lamora/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-11-11-lies-of-locke-lamora/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2eMEhdm">&lt;em>Lies of Locke Lamora&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://www.scottlynch.us/">Scott Lynch&lt;/a> is an engaging fantasy novel set in the city-state of Camorr, which is inspired by Venice. Locke is a leader of a gang called the &lt;em>Gentleman Bastards&lt;/em> who steal from the nobility and other marks using elaborate confidence schemes. The novel spends a lot of time uncovering the history of the &lt;em>Gentleman Bastards&lt;/em>, and delving into the underground of Camorr. This is presented in an engaging manor, but my favorite part of the novel is the way in which Scott Lynch constructs the world Locke operates in. At no point does it feel unnatural. Since, Locke has to have a deep understanding of the world around him the world naturally materializes around him to provide ammo for his impressive heists. The human civilization of Camorr is built on top of a long gone alien civilization, which had a much higher level of technology (and maybe magic). It subtly sits in the background, but begs the question: &lt;em>When we fade will a new civilization use what we have left behind for their infrastructure?&lt;/em> History seems to point to yes, if it is still usable and someone understands how to use it. It is easier to adapt what is present and use it as a natural resource than to tear it down. And those who can use the technology become the priests, witchdoctors and magicians of a new world&amp;hellip; Treating what those long gone took for granted as gods.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Z3 to Find Clock Configurations Values for ARM Cortex Microcontrollers</title><link>/posts/2016-11-06-using-z3-to-find-clock-configurations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-11-06-using-z3-to-find-clock-configurations/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few weeks ago I was setting up multiple embedded systems using the &lt;a href="http://nxp.com">NXP&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://cache.nxp.com/files/microcontrollers/doc/data_sheet/K64P144M120SF5.pdf">Kinetis K64F12&lt;/a> family of microcontrollers. Do to an oversight
a few of the different systems had different input clock frequencies, but all
were intended to work at the same output clock frequency. This is not a major
issue and the ARM Cortex-M4 processors are designed to solve this issue using
a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phase-locked_loop">phase-locked loop (PLL)&lt;/a>. A PLL can take a clock, of one frequency
and output a rather clean clock of another frequency; however, it must be properly
configured. My problem now was a configuration, and mathematics problem. The
parameters are calculated using the following equation:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>$f_{out} = VDIV * \frac{f_{in}}{PRDIV}$, where $VDIV$ and $PRDIV$ are the parameters needed for the configuration. and $f_{in}$ and $f_{out}$ are your input and output frequency which you know ahead of time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A solution to this equation is straightforward but requires a little bit of guessing,
and also checking your answers against a series of constraints specified in the
&lt;a href="http://cache.nxp.com/files/microcontrollers/doc/ref_manual/K64P144M120SF5RM.pdf">datasheet&lt;/a>. The details of this equation and its related constraints
will be approached later. I wanted to automate this task so in
the future I could just adjust these values without having to dig out the &lt;a href="http://cache.nxp.com/files/microcontrollers/doc/ref_manual/K64P144M120SF5RM.pdf">datasheet&lt;/a>
and do the math again. Also to possibly automate making the clock configuration code
to prevent me from being the only person who understood how to configure the clocks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What is someone who loves automation to do? Well, you could solve the equation
directly. However, &lt;a href="https://endless-turtles.com/">Michael Abed&lt;/a> introduced me to a program and
library called &lt;a href="https://github.com/Z3Prover/z3">Z3&lt;/a> which is a constraints solver from
&lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/">Microsoft Research&lt;/a> which I found interesting and wanted to do a
simple project with since I thought it might be useful in the future. Also, this
problem is well-suited as it can take a series of equations and constraints and
search the solution space rather trivially easily. Also, it has a way of deciding
if no solution is possible. So I decided
to use the &lt;a href="https://github.com/Z3Prover/z3">Z3&lt;/a> python bindings to create a python library, with a command line
tool and a web API for solving this problem. This is most certainly overkill, but
considering how easily it all went together I would do it again to solve similar
problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can see the code on &lt;a href="https://github.com/cwoodall/k64-pll-calculator">GitHub&lt;/a> and also play with see the resulting
&lt;a href="http://k64-pll-calculator.herokuapp.com/">website and API demo&lt;/a>. But read on for more details!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Show Your Work by Austin Kleon</title><link>/reading/2016-10-30-show-your-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-10-30-show-your-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2eclEzj">&lt;em>Show Your Work&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://austinkleon.com/">Austin Kleon&lt;/a> was recommended to me by
&lt;a href="https://sivers.org/">Derek Sivers&lt;/a> and he also has &lt;a href="https://sivers.org/book/ShowYourWork">notes posted&lt;/a> which are
rather entertaining and boil down some of the content. I found Austin&amp;rsquo;s book to be
very insightful, and I found it reinforced my resolve to share what I am working
on, be that my reading, music, or hobby engineering projects. There are a lot of
awesome pieces of wisdom hidden in the book about the source of creativity and
the benefits of sharing, but a core principle is found early on in a quote:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Guide To The Good Life by William Irvine</title><link>/reading/2016-10-27-a-guide-to-the-good-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-10-27-a-guide-to-the-good-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the last year I have been reading a lot of Stoic philosophy. I decided to
approached the source texts of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marcus_Aurelius">Marcus Aurelius&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seneca_the_Younger">Seneca The Younger&lt;/a> first. I had been doing well for myself by reading
these very influential texts (most notably
&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2eclCHP">&lt;em>Meditations&lt;/em> by Marcus Aurelius&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2eclmIS">&lt;em>On The Shortness of Life&lt;/em> by Seneca&lt;/a>); however, found myself
desiring some interpretation from a modern perspective to help challenge my
understanding of this philosophy of life. &lt;a href="http://ecbiz147.inmotionhosting.com/~n1stce12/williambirvine.com/">William Irvine&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2fuiHfv">&lt;em>A Guide to The Good Life&lt;/em>&lt;/a> showed up
in a lot of searches and was discussed by &lt;a href="https://sivers.org/">Derek Sivers&lt;/a> in his book
notes. Irvine starts by giving a background of why having a philosophy of life
is critical, and starts to explain why a religion might not fill that role. He
then gives some historical background on Stoicism: first in Greece, and then in
Rome where the version of Stoicism that has been best preserved was formed.
Irvine then launches forward into various pieces of stoic advice and proceeds
to insert his own little quips and opinions in there. Some of the most profound
extractions from the stoic texts were:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Obstacle Is The Way by Ryan Holiday</title><link>/reading/2016-10-21-the-obstacle-is-the-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-10-21-the-obstacle-is-the-way/</guid><description>&lt;p>I listened to &lt;a href="http://ryanholiday.net/">Ryan Holiday&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1591846358/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1591846358&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=cwoo-20&amp;linkId=7a6ccbb78c2b7ad1502f254893455bc0">&lt;em>The Obstacle Is the Way: The Timeless Art of Turning Trials into Triumph&lt;/em>&lt;/a>
as an audiobook on my way back from a weekend of climbing at the &lt;a href="http://www.climbing.com/places/the-gunks-new-york-climbing-destination-guide/">Gunks&lt;/a>.
Climbing always gets me into a reflective and stoic mindset because of that
introspective struggle which involves both meatspace and your internal thought
processes, so I was very receptive to this book on my drive back up. Ryan takes
the approach of inspecting the stories of various successful people throughout
space and time to extract some of the common mental tools used by all of them.
The book is full of great anecdotes, and lessons which you can apply to your
life, but the core piece of knowledge is really in the title. Every obstacle
that life puts in front of us, no matter how bad, can be viewed as an opportunity
after the fact. Who we are is a sum of the obstacles we had to undertake, and
those obstacles are great growth opportunities and should be taken advantage of
rather than shrouded in fear and terror. This is of course easy to say and hard
to do. Some obstacles are terrible and have a very strong psychological impact,
but for many obstacles we face on a day to day basis they are minor and help us
hold a mirror up to ourselves.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Error Handling: Implementing an Option&lt;T> Type For Embedded C++</title><link>/posts/2016-10-10-cpp-option/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2016-10-10-cpp-option/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been learning &lt;a href="http://rust-lang.org">Rust&lt;/a> lately, which has been an awesome and
rewarding experience thus far. However, at work, and on many of my embedded side
projects I use C/C++ quite extensively. But error handling ends up being
a major pain point and can make an otherwise rather simple API into a disaster.
This can be especially true if you are committed to avoiding throwing exceptions for various
performance and real-time reliability reasons. This is where Rust&amp;rsquo;s model comes
in as a possibly solution (or at the very least an interesting one): the use of
the &lt;code>Result&amp;lt;T, E&amp;gt;&lt;/code> types and the &lt;code>Option&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code> type. For the time being I am going to concentrate on the &lt;code>Option&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code> type and write about the &lt;code>Result&amp;lt;T, E&amp;gt;&lt;/code> type in a future post.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The code for this blog post can be found on github as &lt;a href="https://github.com/cwoodall/cpp-option">cpp-option&lt;/a>!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seizing The Enigma by David Kahn</title><link>/reading/2016-10-10-seizing-the-enigma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-10-10-seizing-the-enigma/</guid><description>&lt;p>Daniel Kahn&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2eoZ6Jx">&lt;em>Seizing The Enigma&lt;/em>&lt;/a> is the story of the &lt;em>ENIGMA&lt;/em> machine, a
electro-mechanical cipher system used by the German&amp;rsquo;s during WWII, and &lt;em>ULTRA&lt;/em>
the British code breaking effort of the &lt;em>ENIGMA&lt;/em> (and other Axis encodings and
encipherments). Daniel Kahn is a leading historian of cryptographic history and
it shows in his ability to stitch together a story which does not focus on one
person (such as Turing or Welchman), but instead covers the German&amp;rsquo;s, the navy,
and Bletchley Park (the headquarters of the British code breakers). The descriptions
of the encoding, and code breaking methods, are easy to follow. However, the real
point the book drives home is how pure mathematical analysis is important, but
it in a problem like cryptography it can prove that something is &amp;ldquo;very difficult&amp;rdquo;
to break, without taking into account implementation, and human, details which
change the mathematical facts. The breaking of the &lt;em>ENIGMA&lt;/em> is a beautiful interplay
between mathematical rigor, engineering, espionage and social reasoning. I think
this will change the way I think about problems going forward. This applies not
just in the domain of cryptography, but also safety of systems which have high
consequence. A mathematically provably safe system can be useful, but it is
the social aspects and variables that were not controlled for that can still
cause issues and incidents! This is not to say that we should not provide rigor,
but instead that mathematical and engineering rigor are a basis, and that data
collection and skepticism are necessary to improve and maintain a system.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Superintelligence: Paths, Dangers and Strategies by Nick Bostrom</title><link>/reading/2016-09-24-superintelligence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-09-24-superintelligence/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nick Bostrom&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Superintelligence-Dangers-Strategies-Nick-Bostrom/dp/1501227742">&lt;em>Superintelligence: Paths, Dangers and Strategies&lt;/em>&lt;/a> inspects and dissects the topic of Superintelligence. First, laying out different possible paths to super intelligence and then discussing how these different paths might effect humanity, or might occur. It then discusses the dynamics of a singleton AI and later a multi-polar world of interacting AIs. However, Bostrom&amp;rsquo;s real point throughout this book is not just how one might build an AI. But how one might build and control an AI safely, namely the control problem (which I just found out has a &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ControlProblem/">subreddit&lt;/a> dedicated to it). On one hand Bostrom suggests that human-brain emulation might lead to a super intelligence that naturally shares our values, and with proper selection, there is a small chance this solves the control problem. However, more likely it means we have no real control over what happens. On the other hand, the challenge of building an AI which is set up to be flexible enough to grow with humanity, being benevolent the whole time, and be provably this way is a major challenge in its own right.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Soul of A New Machine by Tracy Kidder</title><link>/reading/2016-09-01-the-soul-of-a-new-machine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-09-01-the-soul-of-a-new-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>I listened to &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2f3klSd">&lt;em>The Soul of A New Machine&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by Tracy Kidder as an Audible audio book on my drive from Boston to NYC and back. It is a rather fast-paced and intense story of the team behind the Data General Eclipse MV/8000, code named Eagle, a 32-bit minicomputer. The book gets into the heads of the various engineers of the project and explains various sub-systems in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms, as well as, how the engineers think of the particular system. You are introduced to a cast of characters quickly termed the Hardyboys and the Microkids based on which subsystems they work on, hardware or the microcode of the processor. These engineers become engulfed in the project and after some time produce the first prototypes Coke and Gollum. From here flows a story of debugging, commitment, and a little bit of insanity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Diamond Age by Neal Stephenson</title><link>/reading/2016-08-14-the-diamond-age/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-08-14-the-diamond-age/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2eS6Bcr">&lt;em>The Diamond Age&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by Neal Stephenson inspects some interesting topics in nano-technology,
tribal societies, and in many ways is a spiritual successor to Snow Crash in that the
general structure of the world is similar. Personally I enjoyed the portion of the book
about the Young Lady&amp;rsquo;s Illustrated Primer and Nell, which explores what can happen
when an underprivileged individual comes into contact with a technology built around
educating and raising children to be strong individuals. The book sort of becomes a little
stale towards the end, the Seed is an interesting technology, but never quite makes sense
and the Drummers and the story that unfolds around them, The Fists of Righteous Harmony,
and John Hackworth (the inventor of the Primer) feels somewhat forced. Like many other
Stephenson books, the ending leaves you wanting more, but the world he has constructed is
interesting enough to satisfy. Think of the book more as a thought experiment in how
tribal societies interact, nano-technology, and a series of other concepts rather than
a concrete story and it will be an enjoyable ride.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Dark Forest by Cixin Liu</title><link>/reading/2016-04-26-the-dark-forest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-04-26-the-dark-forest/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2e2gQtb">&lt;em>The Dark Forest&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liu_Cixin">Cixin Liu&lt;/a> was a thought-provoking book which I think really
does glimpse into the darkness of civilization, and humanity. There is some
subtle optimism presented throughout the book which puts much faith in humanity&amp;rsquo;s (and other civilizations&amp;rsquo;). However, there is also a darkness which is presented which is
a disturbing answer to the Fermi paradox. It is thought provoking and really makes
you contemplate humanity&amp;rsquo;s place in the universe.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Test Driven Development for Embedded C by James Grenning</title><link>/reading/2016-04-13-tdd-in-embedded-c-grenning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-04-13-tdd-in-embedded-c-grenning/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2e2lBTn">&lt;em>Test Driven Development for Embedded C&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://blog.wingman-sw.com/">James Grenning&lt;/a> is a book I heard about through a friend of mine, as well as, through the
&lt;a href="http://embedded.fm/">embedded.fm&lt;/a> embedded systems podcast. It is a well thought
out introduction to TDD in an environment where there is a strong reluctance to
adopt new techniques, and improve code readability, provability and test-ability.
Grenning does a great job at making the sale that TDD is ultimately worth it and
then executes through examples how to test code from scratch, how to add test harnessing
to legacy code, and ultimately how to design code so that it can be tested. To developers
who don&amp;rsquo;t work with C for an embedded platform you might thing this is old hat; however,
for me this book changed the way I think not only of writing C for embedded systems,
but all code. Unit testing has become a standard part of my vocabulary and what I value
in code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Three Body Problem by Cixin Liu</title><link>/reading/2016-04-07-three-body-problem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-04-07-three-body-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://amzn.to/2f3fHDG">&lt;em>Three Body Problem&lt;/em>&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liu_Cixin">Cixin Liu&lt;/a> was a very refreshing near-future sci-fi novel. I really enjoyed the opening of the book and the backdrop of Chinese Culture and history. This gave me new perspective and was novel compared to the tired backdrops of near-future sci-fi, which tend to be western with some superficial Chinese and/or Japanese culture spiked into the mix. As an engineer myself I found Cixin Liu&amp;rsquo;s descriptions of technology to not be too distasteful, he takes his liberties (especially with the Sophons), but in general tries not to depart too far from possibility except where it makes for a good plot device. This book definitely made me question whether humanity even deserves to continue on this planet, a problem the main characters struggle with. I have not quite come to a conclusion, but I do know that I will read the sequel &lt;em>The Dark Forest&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simplified X86 Assembler and Emulator</title><link>/projects/2014-02-03-sx86-emulator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2014-02-03-sx86-emulator/</guid><description>&lt;p>While at BU I had an assignment for a class called EC327 which used a 16-bit
RISC processor that the professors called &amp;ldquo;simplified x86&amp;rdquo;, also referred to as
sx86. This was a very basic assembler, and the tool at the time was written in
java, but had some issues with copying code in and out of the program requiring
that you hand copy the code. To make my debugging easier I implemented an emulator
in Javascript (it should be a valid node.js program), and then a front end to
view the data. I had also written a python script to assemble and dissassemble
these instructions and later integrated a TA for the classes code with mine to
create a CGI based set of calls to assemble and dissassemble the code. I learned
a whole lot more from this project than I would have otherwise, just converting
some machine code by hand and chugging along. This website was used by EC327 for
one or two years after the fact (and may still be today, I have no idea).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>16 Channel 12-bit Floating Fine Adjustment DAC</title><link>/projects/2013-07-30-16-channel-floating-dac/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-30-16-channel-floating-dac/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Artemis Synthesizer v2: Digital Audio Synthesizer Kit</title><link>/projects/2013-07-28-artemis-synth-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-28-artemis-synth-v2/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Artemis Synthesizer is a digital audio synthesizer kit developed in my spare time with help from the &lt;a href="http://edf.bu.edu">BU Electronic Design Facility&lt;/a>. The kits purpose was to help teach a group of female high school freshmen in the &lt;a href="http://www.bu.edu/lernet/artemis/">Artemis&lt;/a> summer program how to solder. Assembly was designed to take between 2 and 4 hours for a beginner, but should take closer to 30 minutes for someone with prior experience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The synthesizer utilizes an ATMega328 and a 12-bit DAC to produce the audio, in its default mode you can play 4 different 8 note scales. There is also a sequencer mode and an ability to change the waveform. To load sequences and new waveforms the &lt;a href="http://cwoodall.github.io/artemis-synth">optoloader&lt;/a> interface is used, which uses javascript to blink a black square on a computer screen and a phototransistor to receive this message, which is then decoded on the microcontroller.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Attaching a Rack To Your Bike with P-Clamps</title><link>/posts/2013-07-07-attach-things-to-your-bike-with-p-clamps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2013-07-07-attach-things-to-your-bike-with-p-clamps/</guid><description>&lt;p>A nice and simple hack for attaching things onto bikes without dropping a ton of money.
Before you buy your P-Clamps, or Rubber Coated Metal Clamps, make sure to measure the
diameter of the tube on your bike you want to attach the clamp to. You can get them from
&lt;a href="http://www.grainger.com/Grainger/ecatalog/N-1z0dvfc">Grainger&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="http://www.mcmaster.com/">McMaster-Carr&lt;/a>, but they are also easily found in your local
hardware store.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TTT: TTC TTS Tester for CMS and G minus 2</title><link>/projects/2013-07-29-ttt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-29-ttt/</guid><description>&lt;p>The TTT is a piece of test equipment design for &lt;a href="http://cms.web.cern.ch/">CMS&lt;/a> through the &lt;a href="http://edf.bu.edu">BU Electronic Design Facility&lt;/a> (EDF). Its main function is to generate L1A (Level-1 Accept) trigger events and stream them to another piece of equipment and listen to that piece of equipment to see if its buffer is full.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The TTT runs a &lt;a href="http://xilinx.com/">Xilinx&lt;/a> Spartan-6 FPGA, with an Ethernet MAC I wrote, and communicates with a PC using a protocol called &lt;a href="https://svnweb.cern.ch/trac/cactus/wiki">IPBus&lt;/a>. This allows for configurations to be set, such as, running off of an external clock. The board to board communications are done over a fiber optic interface and the Spartan-6 chip decodes an 80MHz BiPhase Mark Coded datastream which multiplexes two datastreams together.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monophonic Analog Synthesizer with AR Enveloping</title><link>/projects/2013-07-27-analog-synth-ec412/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-27-analog-synth-ec412/</guid><description>&lt;p>This Monophonic Analog Synthesizer was designed by Christopher Woodall and Benjamin Havey. The synthesizer uses a homemade linearly actuated potentiometer as its input, a long with a button for articulation. The potentiometer voltage is fed through a linear to exponential converter and then a voltage controlled oscillator. The output of the VCO is then put through a analog multiplier designed using an opamp and discrete transistors which envelopes the square and triangle wave VCO outputs with a attack release (AR) envelope. The enveloped output is then filtered, amplified and pumped through speakers. Each piece of the synthesizer was simulated in LTSpice and then built on a breadboard.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Object Detecting Laser Turret</title><link>/projects/2013-07-26-laser-turret-for-ec535/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-26-laser-turret-for-ec535/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Laser Turret uses a webcam to track objects and then shoots a laser in the direction of the tracked object. The goal of is to process the images taken by the webcam and, using the results that comes from processing the images, control the servo motors appropriately to direct the beam of laser at the object. In the time given, we were able to accomplish the goals that we set for ourselves. Using only the gumstix board, we were able to successfully interface with the webcam and process the images taken. We were also able to provide the proper pulse width modulations to the servo motors to correctly aim the laser at the target that the webcam processed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Firestarter v1: Hybrid Rocket Pressure Monitor &amp;amp; Igniter</title><link>/projects/2013-07-29-firestarter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2013 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-29-firestarter/</guid><description>&lt;p>Firestarter v1 was designed to open a pyro valve, preheat the fuel grain, and monitor the combustion chamber and N2O tank pressures for the &lt;a href="http://www.burocket.org/">BU Rocket Propulsion Group&lt;/a>&amp;rsquo;s MkIII hybrid rocket engine. The pressure readings are all from full bridge pressure transducers which go through an instrumentation amplifier, 4th order Butterwirth filter and into an ADC. The board communicates to the world through and RS-422 connection and runs on STM32 Cortex-M3 microcontroller. More explicit information is not available due to various restrictions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>builds.cc v2</title><link>/projects/2013-08-15-builds-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-08-15-builds-website/</guid><description/></item><item><title>NES Controller Controlled LED Cube</title><link>/projects/2013-08-30-nes-controlled-led-cube/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-08-30-nes-controlled-led-cube/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Twelve Ounce: A Low-Cost Robot for Experimentation</title><link>/projects/2013-07-30-twelve-ounce/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-30-twelve-ounce/</guid><description/></item><item><title>C4: Connect 4 Android Game</title><link>/projects/2013-07-30-c4-android/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-30-c4-android/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever wanted to Connect Four red or blue disks on a yellow background? Now is your chance! This implementation of the fun and traditional game utilizes the Android NDK, a C++ backend and the native Java SDK.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Play single player, against a silly AI, or against a Friend in an epic duel of the whits.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NOMIS: Simon Memory Game Clone</title><link>/projects/2013-07-30-nomis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/projects/2013-07-30-nomis/</guid><description>&lt;p>Nomis is a Simon-like memory game for the ATTiny85, which uses the ATTiny85. The game logic in the ATTiny85 was implemented using AVR C and takes up 983 bytes in program memory and 6 bytes in data memory. The implementation size comes in under 1kB, but could most certainly be smaller. The pin usage, however, is very conservative and the games electronics take up a total of 4 of the 6 available pins. The 4 LEDs are controlled on 3 pins using Charlieplexing model (which could easily be extended to 6 LEDs). On the other hand the 4 pushbutton switches are feed into an ADC input through an R2R ladder configuration. I am very happy with the limited pin usage of this project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christopher Woodall - Music</title><link>/music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/music/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recent music under the name TemporalShift&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="300" scrolling="no" frameborder="no" allow="autoplay" src="https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/1196276950&amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;auto_play=false&amp;hide_related=false&amp;show_comments=true&amp;show_user=true&amp;show_reposts=false&amp;show_teaser=true&amp;visual=true">&lt;/iframe>&lt;div style="font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;">&lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/temporalshift" title="TemporalShift" target="_blank" style="color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;">TemporalShift&lt;/a> · &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/temporalshift/knight-of-infinite-resignation" title="Knight Of Infinite Resignation" target="_blank" style="color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;">Knight Of Infinite Resignation&lt;/a>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>I have been trying to write down and publish some of my notes about mandolin, and other scores using &lt;a href="https://musescore.org">MuseScore 3.6&lt;/a>. Please check into my &lt;a href="https://github.com/cwoodall/scores">scores github repository&lt;/a> to follow along! So far I have tabs + sheet music up for:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>