<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Climbings on Chris Woodall</title><link>/climbing/</link><description>Recent content in Climbings on Chris Woodall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/climbing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>31 Climbs</title><link>/climbing/2023-04-01-31-climbs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/climbing/2023-04-01-31-climbs/</guid><description>This year I turned 31, which is not an auspicious year; other than it being the last year that you can represent on one hand counting in binary (2^5-1). So I went down to MetroRock in Essex, VT and spent about 5 hours in the gym getting my 31 climbs together with support from friends and loved ones. To plan I started by listing out some rules:
Climb on ropes only or if doing boulders you need to link to rope length.</description></item><item><title>Mt. Avalon Trip Report</title><link>/climbing/2018-03-13-mt-avalon-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/climbing/2018-03-13-mt-avalon-report/</guid><description>On Saturday March 10, 2018 Don, Toni and I ventured out to Mt. Avalon. With the NEClimbs Ice Report looking rather pessimistic we deiced to go somewhere with no reported ice condition information. I figured the less we knew about the ice the better off we were. So we woke up bright and early, got ourselves some food at Patches and then leisurely waited for Bear Notch Ski and Snowshoe Rentals to open so we could rent ourselves a pair of snowshoes for our little bushwack.</description></item><item><title>Gear Review: Anker Ice Screw Holder</title><link>/climbing/2018-02-06-gear-review-anker-ice-screw-holder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/climbing/2018-02-06-gear-review-anker-ice-screw-holder/</guid><description>I just got myself the Anker Equipment screw holder for my brand new rack of ice screws. This thing was $45.00 and holds 12 screws. It even has a little pouch in the middle which can fit a 10cm screw, or file depending on what you want to use it for. Generally speaking I found it to be rather compact compared to the BD offering. It fits 12 screws nicely and folds up to a rather compact size.</description></item><item><title>Squamish Trip Report</title><link>/climbing/2018-02-19-squamish-trip-report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/climbing/2018-02-19-squamish-trip-report/</guid><description>This summer I went to Squamish from August 11th-18th, 2017 with Alice Chiang, and a group made up of Matt, Lauren, Tiff and Josh. I climbed with Alice throughout the trip and had an awesome time on the splitter and reasonably high-friction granite found at Squamish. I had been once before on 2016 and had an objective in mind I had recruited Alice for: an ascent of the first peak of the Chief via Calculus Crack, and Squamish Butt Face.</description></item></channel></rss>