<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nows on Chris Woodall</title><link>/now/</link><description>Recent content in Nows on Chris Woodall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 12:05:42 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/now/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>July 2021</title><link>/now/2021-07-18/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 12:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>/now/2021-07-18/</guid><description>What am I doing now? Working on electric aircraft at BETA Technologies Continuing to love Obsidian.md Working on generative art Taking notes using Obsidian, generating art using Kotlin and OpenRNDR, and publishing using neuron Getting more into mountain biking Preparing to run a 8k in August and a half-marathon in October Preparing for 2 weeks in the PNW in September My priorities are: Building strong habits around going getting enough sleep, improved health and improved sleep Getting a personal task management solution that works for me in place Quotes On My Mind The Buddha told his disciples, “Believe nothing, no matter where you read it, or who said it, no matter if I have said it, unless it agrees with your own reason and your own common sense.</description></item><item><title>January 2021</title><link>/now/2021-01-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 12:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>/now/2021-01-01/</guid><description>What am I doing now? Working on electric aircraft at BETA Technologies Skiing! Playing around with note taking in Obsidian.md Learning a little Rust each day. My priorities are: Building strong habits around going to sleep, waking up, doing deep work, and building new skills Quotes On My Mind Only ideas won by walking have any value
&amp;ndash; Friedrich Nietzsche
Forty hour workweeks are a relic of the Industrial Age.</description></item><item><title>November 2020</title><link>/now/2020-11-28/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 12:05:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>/now/2020-11-28/</guid><description>What am I doing now? Working at BETA Technologies on electric aviation, still working on electric propulsion. I have been playing mandolin regularly, and making improvements slowly Getting ready for ski and ice season, by climbing at the gym more. My priorities are: Deepening and continuing my practice of Buddhism Treating my body well by exercising and eating nourishing foods Continuing to develop expertise in motor controls. Quotes On My Mind Simply begin again</description></item><item><title>February 2020</title><link>/now/2020-02-01/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/now/2020-02-01/</guid><description>What am I doing now? Reflecting on 2019, it was a crazy year with a lot to learn on a personal level.
I am now in Burlington, VT working at BETA Technologies on the future of electric aviation! My main focus is on inverters for controlling motors. This is taking up most of my time.
I have been meditating daily (using a combination of Unified Mindfulness and Sam Harris' Waking Up app), trying to do daily creative acts (water colors, music, programming, etc), and when I can going to yoga.</description></item></channel></rss>