<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Readings on Chris Woodall</title><link>/reading/</link><description>Recent content in Readings on Chris Woodall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recursion by Blake Crouch</title><link>/reading/2020-02-14-recursion/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2020-02-14-recursion/</guid><description>Recursion by Blake Crouch is an interesting take on a time travel thriller, involving characters and relationships across multiple time lines. It is interesting how some of the characters who at first seem minor become integral parts of the story, developing into more interesting and intelligent characters over their recursions, creating small perturbations leading to different lives, but infrequently to different outcomes. What does it mean to try to change the present by going into the past?</description></item><item><title>Fear and Trembling by Kierkegaard</title><link>/reading/2018-11-01-fear-and-trembling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-11-01-fear-and-trembling/</guid><description/></item><item><title>21 Lessons for the 21st Century by Yuval Noah Harari</title><link>/reading/2018-10-28-21-lessons-for-the-21st-century/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-10-28-21-lessons-for-the-21st-century/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Myth of Sisyphus by Camus</title><link>/reading/2018-09-23-myth-of-sisyphus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-09-23-myth-of-sisyphus/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Apology by Plato</title><link>/reading/2018-08-13-apology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-08-13-apology/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Crux by Ramez Naam</title><link>/reading/2018-07-30-the-crux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-07-30-the-crux/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Espresso Lessons by Arno Ilgner</title><link>/reading/2018-07-11-espresso-lessons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-07-11-espresso-lessons/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Roadside Picnic by Arkady and Boris Strugatsky</title><link>/reading/2018-07-02-roadside-picnic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-07-02-roadside-picnic/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Miracle of Mindfulness by Thich Nhat Hahn</title><link>/reading/2018-06-23-the-miracle-of-mindfulness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-06-23-the-miracle-of-mindfulness/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Desert Solitaire by Edward Abbey</title><link>/reading/2018-06-07-desert-solitaire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-06-07-desert-solitaire/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Wandering Earth by Cixin Liu</title><link>/reading/2018-04-17-the-wandering-earth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-04-17-the-wandering-earth/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dharma Bums by Jack Kerouac</title><link>/reading/2018-03-18-dharma-bums/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-03-18-dharma-bums/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Climb Strong by Steve Betchel</title><link>/reading/2018-03-07-climb-strong/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-03-07-climb-strong/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rock Climbers Training Manual by Mark L. Anderson and Michael L. Anderson</title><link>/reading/2018-01-03-rock-climbers-training-manual/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2018 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2018-01-03-rock-climbers-training-manual/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mistborn: The Final Empire (Book 1) by Brandon Sanderson</title><link>/reading/2017-12-30-mistborn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-12-30-mistborn/</guid><description>A few of my friends have been trying to get me to read a book by Brandon Sanderson for quite some time. Given that I enjoyed Rothfuss' Name of the Wind, and Lynch&amp;rsquo;s The Lies of Locke Lamora I thought a good starting place would be Mistborn: The Final Empire, which have a similar setup. The best thing about Mistborn is the world it is set in, and the fascinating and engaging pace with which new details are introduced about the world, characters and magic systems.</description></item><item><title>The Odyssey by Homer (Translated by Richard Fagles)</title><link>/reading/2017-12-13-the-odyssey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-12-13-the-odyssey/</guid><description>Homer&amp;rsquo;s The Odyssey, as translated by Richard Fagles, is a classic. The Fagles translation reads very naturally to a native English speaker. While I am sure there are some trade-offs when compared to a more literal translation, I felt that this translation was very enjoyable. I read this epic because it is a foundational text of the western literary tradition, and it really shows in it&amp;rsquo;s influence on other works. The form, the characters, and the motivations are all so familiar even though the original story is from so long go.</description></item><item><title>The Graveyard Book by Neil Gaiman</title><link>/reading/2017-11-22-graveyard-book/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-11-22-graveyard-book/</guid><description>I started listening to The Graveyard Book by Neil Gaiman while I was in JFK airport in NY. I had missed a connecting flight and was alone in the airport for those early morning hours where the bustling of the airport stops. The ambiance of the airport fit the tone of the book. I really enjoyed the story-telling. Part of it was that the Audible full-cast production was very well done and the writing style fits an audiobook.</description></item><item><title>The Weather Makers by Tim Flannery</title><link>/reading/2017-10-10-weather-makers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-10-10-weather-makers/</guid><description>The Weather Makers by Tim Flannery is a frightening and enlightening book about global warming. Though it is about 10 years old at this point it had a few major points:
The evidence for human linked global warming is very strong (and has only become stronger) The reduction in biodiversity is intense, and probably irreversible; we have changed climates and biomes and there is probably no going back. There is no silver bullet, we need all nations to collaborate and the issues are largely policy issues.</description></item><item><title>A Wizard of Earthsea by Ursula K. Le Guin</title><link>/reading/2017-10-09-a-wizard-of-earthsea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-10-09-a-wizard-of-earthsea/</guid><description>A Wizard of Earthsea by Ursula K. Le Guin is a fun fantasy novel aimed at young adults and teens. It follows a wizard named Ged/Sparrowhawk as he tries to get rid of an evil he brought into the world through his own arrogance. It is well written and enjoyable, like Left Hand of Darkness the world building is superb and is given to you in little shards as you need to know about it.</description></item><item><title>Left Hand of Darkness by Ursula K. Le Guin</title><link>/reading/2017-09-30-left-hand-of-darkness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-09-30-left-hand-of-darkness/</guid><description>What would it be like on a world where everyone was an asexual hermaphrodite 99% of the time? Where gender and sex were not the primary focus of day to day life, because most of the time everyone was the same in this regard? Left Hand of Darkness by Ursula K. Le Guin thrusts Genly Ai, a run of the mill male Terran human, into the middle of the planet Winter where the inhabitants fit this description.</description></item><item><title>Nexus by Ramez Naam</title><link>/reading/2017-08-20-nexus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-08-20-nexus/</guid><description>Nexus by Ramez Naam is a science fiction book which takes place in the near future, where technology has been created to link human minds, and possibly control them. Naam inspects different social impacts of these technologies ranging from the most profound and inspirational uses (such as building new levels of empath and human connection) to the most disturbing and dark abuses (such as making it trivial to coerce people). The technology seems and feels plausible throughout the novel, besides towards the end where a few flimsy cyberpunk-esque plot devices are used to move the story forward.</description></item><item><title>Dune by Frank Herbert</title><link>/reading/2017-07-27-dune/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-07-27-dune/</guid><description>I finally read Frank Herbert&amp;rsquo;s classic novel Dune after avoiding it for a long time. My father gave me a copy after finishing the [Lord of the Rings] during middle-school. At the time I found the book to be slow and overly political, but I came back to it at the perfect time. The world rife with political unrest and I am more capable of dealing the the moral ambiguity of the work.</description></item><item><title>Beyond The Vertical by Layton Kor</title><link>/reading/2017-06-26-beyond-the-vertical/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-06-26-beyond-the-vertical/</guid><description>Beyond The Vertical by Layton Kor follows the climbing career from childhood into old age of the author. The format of the book is a series of short vignettes of different climbing trips from a wide variety of Layton&amp;rsquo;s partners (including Steve Roper, Jim McCarthy and Royal Robbins) glued together by Layton&amp;rsquo;s own recounting of his climbing career. The descriptions of their approach to climbing, and the shear sense of adventure that compelled them inspires me as a human and as a climber.</description></item><item><title>Sapiens by Yuval Noah Harari</title><link>/reading/2017-06-14-sapiens/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-06-14-sapiens/</guid><description>Humans are story-tellers, we communicated by telling others about our experiences, about those of others, and most interestingly about things that never even happened. These stories create a shared network of knowledge and information, which allow us to cooperate and form networks of trust, and eventually layer on top of each other to form concepts like money, religion and the nation-state. Sapiens by Yuval Noah Harari explores and reveals pieces of the story telling nature of humanity and reveals the good and the bad of this.</description></item><item><title>Tribe by Sebastian Junger</title><link>/reading/2017-05-02-tribe/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-05-02-tribe/</guid><description>Sebastian Junger&amp;rsquo;s Tribe is a short but poignant book about the transition from childhood to adulthood and belonging. The book seems to focus on a male perspective, but is not exclusionary so much as just very specific. The focus is on how do humans adapt from being part of groups—such as the military, where they have a strong sense of belonging, purpose and brotherhood—to being single independent units which are so common in modern America.</description></item><item><title>Barbarian Days: A Surfing Life by William Finnegan</title><link>/reading/2017-04-27-barbarian-days/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-04-27-barbarian-days/</guid><description>[William Finnegan&amp;rsquo;s] book Barbarian Days: A Surfing Life follows the authors obsession with surfing, from his childhood to adulthood with a long section of being a surf bum in between. I have never surfed, but I found myself being dragged into the lingo and culture and really yearning in a way for that open life adventure. For me climbing fits a similar role in my life, I know to some degree it is pointless, yet I come back to it and it keeps providing something for me.</description></item><item><title>Hard-Boiled Wonderland and the End of The World by Haruki Murakami</title><link>/reading/2017-03-29-hard-boiled-wonderland-end-of-the-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-03-29-hard-boiled-wonderland-end-of-the-world/</guid><description>Hard-Boiled Wonderland and the End of The World by Haruki Murakami involves 2 parallel, seemingly unrelated stories, which become more and more intertwined as the stories develop. One of them takes place in a cyberpunk like future, with humans who act as encryption/decryption services, and the other in a surreal fantasy land where your shadow is removed from you and you can&amp;rsquo;t leave. The story is intriguing and I can&amp;rsquo;t discuss it much more without spoiling, but I found it to be thought provoking and it was a little bit of a smoother read than other Murakami books, but still had all of the beautiful and delicate language which Murakami does so well.</description></item><item><title>Kafka on the Shore by Haruki Murakami</title><link>/reading/2017-03-09-kafka-on-the-shore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-03-09-kafka-on-the-shore/</guid><description>Haruki Murakami&amp;rsquo;s Kafka on the Shore is an elegantly written book filled with heady references and a magical-realism which penetrates this abstract reinterpretation of Oedipus Rex. The setting is outstanding, describing not just Japan, but all of the subtly magical pieces of the world. The spiritual becomes an integral part of the novel, and nothing is literal. It stretches your mind as a seemingly direct prophecy is carried out through the most abstract and dream-like of means.</description></item><item><title>Good Omens by Terry Pratchett and Neil Gaiman</title><link>/reading/2017-03-06-good-omens/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-03-06-good-omens/</guid><description>Good Omens is a collaboration between Terry Pratchett and Neil Gaiman which I listened to as an audiobook. A humorous, satirical and biting novel about the apocalypse, starring a demon who is not so bad, an angel who is not so good, and an anti-christ who just wants to play with his friends. I found it to be hilarious, with a lot of funny social and religious commentary. The book feels mostly like Terry Pratchett, with a little bit of the unique darkness Neil Gaiman brings; however, I think the collaboration was very successful.</description></item><item><title>Norse Mythology by Neil Gaiman</title><link>/reading/2017-02-26-norse-mythology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-02-26-norse-mythology/</guid><description>Neil Gaiman&amp;rsquo;s Norse Mythology is retelling of the myths of the Norse God&amp;rsquo;s focusing mainly on: Thor, Loki, Odin, Freya and Frey. I listend to the audiobook, narrated by Neil Gaiman, which I thought was well done, and felt personal. The stories are engaging and well told. The book approaches the perfect blend of myth and narrative, and it extends from being a creative work in its own right. The myths are accessible, but still they leave a strong impression, and a strong curiosity to learn more about the bizarre world of the Norse gods, and their massive flaws.</description></item><item><title>Breakfast of Champions by Kurt Vonnegut</title><link>/reading/2017-02-13-breakfast-of-champions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-02-13-breakfast-of-champions/</guid><description>This is my second time reading Kurt Vonnegut&amp;rsquo;s Breakfast of Champions. When I first read this book I appreciated the appreciated the dark sarcasm, humor and absurdism, but I never appreciated what they were doing. This is a book written by an author to himself as a deeply introspective work about his own creativity. A world created to make vulnerable the author himself, to insect life and use a work of fiction to explain itself.</description></item><item><title>Death's End by Cixin Liu</title><link>/reading/2017-02-02-deaths-end/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2017-02-02-deaths-end/</guid><description>Cixin Liu&amp;rsquo;s last book in the Three Body Problem trilogy, Death&amp;rsquo;s End, is a break in format from the last two books in the series. It starts before the first book and ends millions (or possibly billions) of years afterwards following the life of Cheng Xin, a aerospace engineer who ends up making some of the most important decisions for humanity. Where the last two books are rather focused in scope this book has the feel of Isaac Asimov, or Arthur C.</description></item><item><title>Lies of Locke Lamora by Scott Lynch</title><link>/reading/2016-11-11-lies-of-locke-lamora/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-11-11-lies-of-locke-lamora/</guid><description>The Lies of Locke Lamora by Scott Lynch is an engaging fantasy novel set in the city-state of Camorr, which is inspired by Venice. Locke is a leader of a gang called the Gentleman Bastards who steal from the nobility and other marks using elaborate confidence schemes. The novel spends a lot of time uncovering the history of the Gentleman Bastards, and delving into the underground of Camorr. This is presented in an engaging manor, but my favorite part of the novel is the way in which Scott Lynch constructs the world Locke operates in.</description></item><item><title>Show Your Work by Austin Kleon</title><link>/reading/2016-10-30-show-your-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-10-30-show-your-work/</guid><description>Show Your Work by Austin Kleon was recommended to me by Derek Sivers and he also has notes posted which are rather entertaining and boil down some of the content. I found Austin&amp;rsquo;s book to be very insightful, and I found it reinforced my resolve to share what I am working on, be that my reading, music, or hobby engineering projects. There are a lot of awesome pieces of wisdom hidden in the book about the source of creativity and the benefits of sharing, but a core principle is found early on in a quote:</description></item><item><title>A Guide To The Good Life by William Irvine</title><link>/reading/2016-10-27-a-guide-to-the-good-life/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-10-27-a-guide-to-the-good-life/</guid><description>Over the last year I have been reading a lot of Stoic philosophy. I decided to approached the source texts of Marcus Aurelius and Seneca The Younger first. I had been doing well for myself by reading these very influential texts (most notably Meditations by Marcus Aurelius and On The Shortness of Life by Seneca); however, found myself desiring some interpretation from a modern perspective to help challenge my understanding of this philosophy of life.</description></item><item><title>The Obstacle Is The Way by Ryan Holiday</title><link>/reading/2016-10-21-the-obstacle-is-the-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-10-21-the-obstacle-is-the-way/</guid><description>I listened to Ryan Holiday&amp;rsquo;s The Obstacle Is the Way: The Timeless Art of Turning Trials into Triumph as an audiobook on my way back from a weekend of climbing at the Gunks. Climbing always gets me into a reflective and stoic mindset because of that introspective struggle which involves both meatspace and your internal thought processes, so I was very receptive to this book on my drive back up. Ryan takes the approach of inspecting the stories of various successful people throughout space and time to extract some of the common mental tools used by all of them.</description></item><item><title>Seizing The Enigma by David Kahn</title><link>/reading/2016-10-10-seizing-the-enigma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 12:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-10-10-seizing-the-enigma/</guid><description>Daniel Kahn&amp;rsquo;s Seizing The Enigma is the story of the ENIGMA machine, a electro-mechanical cipher system used by the German&amp;rsquo;s during WWII, and ULTRA the British code breaking effort of the ENIGMA (and other Axis encodings and encipherments). Daniel Kahn is a leading historian of cryptographic history and it shows in his ability to stitch together a story which does not focus on one person (such as Turing or Welchman), but instead covers the German&amp;rsquo;s, the navy, and Bletchley Park (the headquarters of the British code breakers).</description></item><item><title>Superintelligence: Paths, Dangers and Strategies by Nick Bostrom</title><link>/reading/2016-09-24-superintelligence/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-09-24-superintelligence/</guid><description>Nick Bostrom&amp;rsquo;s Superintelligence: Paths, Dangers and Strategies inspects and dissects the topic of Superintelligence. First, laying out different possible paths to super intelligence and then discussing how these different paths might effect humanity, or might occur. It then discusses the dynamics of a singleton AI and later a multi-polar world of interacting AIs. However, Bostrom&amp;rsquo;s real point throughout this book is not just how one might build an AI. But how one might build and control an AI safely, namely the control problem (which I just found out has a subreddit dedicated to it).</description></item><item><title>The Soul of A New Machine by Tracy Kidder</title><link>/reading/2016-09-01-the-soul-of-a-new-machine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-09-01-the-soul-of-a-new-machine/</guid><description>I listened to The Soul of A New Machine by Tracy Kidder as an Audible audio book on my drive from Boston to NYC and back. It is a rather fast-paced and intense story of the team behind the Data General Eclipse MV/8000, code named Eagle, a 32-bit minicomputer. The book gets into the heads of the various engineers of the project and explains various sub-systems in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms, as well as, how the engineers think of the particular system.</description></item><item><title>The Diamond Age by Neal Stephenson</title><link>/reading/2016-08-14-the-diamond-age/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 15:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-08-14-the-diamond-age/</guid><description>The Diamond Age by Neal Stephenson inspects some interesting topics in nano-technology, tribal societies, and in many ways is a spiritual successor to Snow Crash in that the general structure of the world is similar. Personally I enjoyed the portion of the book about the Young Lady&amp;rsquo;s Illustrated Primer and Nell, which explores what can happen when an underprivileged individual comes into contact with a technology built around educating and raising children to be strong individuals.</description></item><item><title>The Dark Forest by Cixin Liu</title><link>/reading/2016-04-26-the-dark-forest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-04-26-the-dark-forest/</guid><description>The Dark Forest by Cixin Liu was a thought-provoking book which I think really does glimpse into the darkness of civilization, and humanity. There is some subtle optimism presented throughout the book which puts much faith in humanity&amp;rsquo;s (and other civilizations'). However, there is also a darkness which is presented which is a disturbing answer to the Fermi paradox. It is thought provoking and really makes you contemplate humanity&amp;rsquo;s place in the universe.</description></item><item><title>Test Driven Development for Embedded C by James Grenning</title><link>/reading/2016-04-13-tdd-in-embedded-c-grenning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-04-13-tdd-in-embedded-c-grenning/</guid><description>Test Driven Development for Embedded C by James Grenning is a book I heard about through a friend of mine, as well as, through the embedded.fm embedded systems podcast. It is a well thought out introduction to TDD in an environment where there is a strong reluctance to adopt new techniques, and improve code readability, provability and test-ability. Grenning does a great job at making the sale that TDD is ultimately worth it and then executes through examples how to test code from scratch, how to add test harnessing to legacy code, and ultimately how to design code so that it can be tested.</description></item><item><title>Three Body Problem by Cixin Liu</title><link>/reading/2016-04-07-three-body-problem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/reading/2016-04-07-three-body-problem/</guid><description>The Three Body Problem by Cixin Liu was a very refreshing near-future sci-fi novel. I really enjoyed the opening of the book and the backdrop of Chinese Culture and history. This gave me new perspective and was novel compared to the tired backdrops of near-future sci-fi, which tend to be western with some superficial Chinese and/or Japanese culture spiked into the mix. As an engineer myself I found Cixin Liu&amp;rsquo;s descriptions of technology to not be too distasteful, he takes his liberties (especially with the Sophons), but in general tries not to depart too far from possibility except where it makes for a good plot device.</description></item></channel></rss>