<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chris Woodall</title>
    <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chris Woodall</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 17:44:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cwoodall.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is The Output Of Your Work?</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2020-11-27-output-of-your-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 17:44:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2020-11-27-output-of-your-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, while in the middle of a big product release, I turned to a co-worker and asked them:
&lt;strong&gt;What is the output of your work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This sounds like a silly question, but I found it to be enlightening to reflect on. Here we were, stressed out about
making something. However, what we were really doing was producing the documentation, the knowledge, and the confidence
in the product we were making. It is easy to get lost in the idea that what you produce is the
gizmo, gadget, or the most tactile result of your actions. In some ways it is tempting to think that if you paint you produce a
painting; if you write music you produce a song; if you write code it is the website or demo that is the output of your work.
On reflection I found that while the direct goal is often one output of your work, in many ways is more a side-effect.
In this view the main output is the information, experience, and documentation that is created by the process of doing the work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection in C&#43;&#43; to Generate Serializable Structs Using libclang and Python</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2018-02-24-using-clang-and-python-to-generate-cpp-struct-serde-fns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 17:44:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2018-02-24-using-clang-and-python-to-generate-cpp-struct-serde-fns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have recently found myself writing a bunch of serialization (and
deserialization) functions in C++ for some very basic structs, and
classes. Each of these serialization functions has the same basic
form which is basically a series of function calls to convert
some data of some type into it&amp;rsquo;s msgpack representation. As the
number of structs grows this becomes tedious and hard to upgrade. Also,
there are a few points where programmer error can result in major hard
to detect problems, if the ordering is wrong, or the number of fields
is wrong, then all bets are off. I will be the first to admit that
Google Protobufs basically solves this problem entirely by describing
the transfer messages, and datatypes in its own language and then
compiling the target representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by my recent usage of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rust-lang.org/en-US/&#34;&gt;rust&lt;/a&gt; I decided to see if I could create
the equivalent of rust&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;#[derive()]&lt;/code&gt; syntax for applying  procedural
macros to a struct. You can see my experiment on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cwoodall/cpp-serde-gen&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Manage My Reading List With Trello</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2017-10-16-how-i-manage-my-reading-list-with-trello/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2017-10-16-how-i-manage-my-reading-list-with-trello/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In college I frequently would go on book reading binges during breaks, but I could not keep
myself to a consistent schedule to read for pleasure during classes. This &amp;ldquo;not enough
time&amp;rdquo; syndrome carried over to after I left college, even though I was not actually
particularly busy outside of work. Missing reading I started to gather books I wanted
to read, but was having trouble keeping track of all of them, and sorting through what
to read next. So I gave some reason to the madness by using
&lt;a href=&#34;http://trello.com&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;. You can view my
&lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/b/9l0rYMxD/reading-list&#34;&gt;Trello Reading List&lt;/a&gt; and see what I
have on there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally by maintaining a list which is so flexible and easy to manipulate I
have added some tangibility to the abstract concept of &amp;ldquo;books I want to read&amp;rdquo;. I
can also track and set goals related to reading rate and diversity of books since
I maintain all of that data. Another plus is that it makes it easy to track what
I need to write blurbs for my website. Some of my friends use other systems,
including &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/&#34;&gt;goodreads&lt;/a&gt; and just maintaining a literal
(and literary) stack of books. I like the Trello system because it felt easier to
abandon my reading past, than it did on goodreads, which made it feel like I should
log every book I have read since birth. That said the friends I have who use
goodreads seem to like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on for more information on how I organize my Trello reading list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making GIFs From Videos in Linux</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-12-24-making-gifs-from-videos-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 18:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-12-24-making-gifs-from-videos-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started making some &lt;code&gt;.gif&lt;/code&gt;s to embed in documentation and my notes as I
develop &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cwoodall/rusty-nail&#34;&gt;Rusty Nail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I always have to lookup how to
convert the images to &lt;code&gt;gif&lt;/code&gt;s. Every time I am also concerned with how big the
&lt;code&gt;.gif&lt;/code&gt;s are so after doing some looking around I made a little script which
uses &lt;code&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;convert&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;gifsicle&lt;/code&gt; (with &lt;code&gt;giflossy&lt;/code&gt;) to take an input
&lt;code&gt;mp4&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;webm&lt;/code&gt;, or any video that ffmpeg can decode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;ffmpeg&lt;/code&gt; splits the video into a directory of &lt;code&gt;gif&lt;/code&gt;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;convert&lt;/code&gt; those images and stitches them together into one &lt;code&gt;gif&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gifsicle&lt;/code&gt; optimizes the &lt;code&gt;gif&lt;/code&gt; and allow a stage to resize it and also change
the color. The &lt;code&gt;giflossy&lt;/code&gt; plug-in also can apply lossy compression to the
gif video during the optimization step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on for the script.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My New Bash Prompt: Exit Codes, Unicode and Git Branches</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-12-19-my-new-bash-prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 20:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-12-19-my-new-bash-prompt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided to customize my bash prompt. I initially started off with
the following requirements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should be two lines! I have found that having the input and my prompt on
one line is not enough space most of the time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to see my current git branch, and also if there are any uncommitted
changes in the current branch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I want to see my username, host name and current directory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current directory should be truncated so that it shows the 4 closest
directories in the path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The status if the previous command should be show in some way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some work I came up with the prompt shown above. I am excited to keep
using it and customizing it, I am also happy that I decided to use unicode in
the prompt. I have been avoiding unicode in general, but
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rustlang.com&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; has convinced me that I should try to accept
unicode into my life more readily!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After going through the process, here are sometake aways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;printf&lt;/code&gt; supports unicode more reliably than echo. I had some trouble
getting echo to do what I want to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I always forget this one. Bash functions are never what I think they are.
They  are  scripts you can define inside of a script. I
always seem to find this causing problems for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoy! Below is the code for my prompt! Put it into you
&lt;code&gt;.profile&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.bash_profile&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;.bashrc&lt;/code&gt; file depending on your preference. If
you want to use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts On the Coursera Machine Learning Course</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-12-18-thoughts-on-coursera-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-12-18-thoughts-on-coursera-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I completed my first &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; course, which was
&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning&#34;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.andrewng.org/&#34;&gt;Andrew Ng&lt;/a&gt; from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.stanford.edu/&#34;&gt;Stanford University&lt;/a&gt;. The course was well
taught and concentrates on building a solid base for applying
Machine Learning to a variety of problems. Andrew Ng uses examples
motivated by real-world problems to show how you might apply the algorithms
taught. I highly recommend the course if you are looking to take a MOOC and have
an interest in machine learning. I learnt a lot, but still need to apply the
knowledge in some personal projects of mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on for more thoughts on the course and tips on how to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing libsvm For Use With GNU Octave In Ubuntu 14.04</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-11-19-installing-libsvm-for-octave-in-ubuntu-14-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-11-19-installing-libsvm-for-octave-in-ubuntu-14-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For week 7 of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://coursera.com/&#34;&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning/home&#34;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; course we
learned about &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Support_vector_machine&#34;&gt;Support Vector Machines (SVM)&lt;/a&gt;. SVMs are a useful and
powerful tools for solving classification problems. They can be tailored to
solve complicated classification boundaries, and don&amp;rsquo;t suffer from some of the
down sides of optimizing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_neural_network&#34;&gt;neural networks&lt;/a&gt;. One of the
example problems uses an SVM to classify spam emails. A SVM implementation
written in MATLAB/Octave is used, but for further work &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csie.ntu.edu.tw/~cjlin/libsvm/&#34;&gt;libsvm&lt;/a&gt; (or
another SVM library) is recommended. To get &lt;code&gt;libsvm&lt;/code&gt; working with Octave in
Ubuntu 14.04 there are a few steps that are not obvious. I did not find very
many instructions so I compiled the steps I followed to get a stable Octave
environment with &lt;code&gt;libsvm&lt;/code&gt;. Read on for details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Z3 to Find Clock Configurations Values for ARM Cortex Microcontrollers</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-11-06-using-z3-to-find-clock-configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-11-06-using-z3-to-find-clock-configurations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I was setting up multiple embedded systems using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://nxp.com&#34;&gt;NXP&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cache.nxp.com/files/microcontrollers/doc/data_sheet/K64P144M120SF5.pdf&#34;&gt;Kinetis K64F12&lt;/a&gt; family of microcontrollers. Do to an oversight
a few of the different systems had different input clock frequencies, but all
were intended to work at the same output clock frequency. This is not a major
issue and the ARM Cortex-M4 processors are designed to solve this issue using
a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phase-locked_loop&#34;&gt;phase-locked loop (PLL)&lt;/a&gt;. A PLL can take a clock, of one frequency
and output a rather clean clock of another frequency; however, it must be properly
configured. My problem now was a configuration, and mathematics problem. The
parameters are calculated using the following equation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$f_{out} = VDIV * \frac{f_{in}}{PRDIV}$, where $VDIV$ and $PRDIV$ are the parameters needed for the configuration. and $f_{in}$ and $f_{out}$ are your input and output frequency which you know ahead of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A solution to this equation is straightforward but requires a little bit of guessing,
and also checking your answers against a series of constraints specified in the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://cache.nxp.com/files/microcontrollers/doc/ref_manual/K64P144M120SF5RM.pdf&#34;&gt;datasheet&lt;/a&gt;. The details of this equation and its related constraints
will be approached later. I wanted to automate this task so in
the future I could just adjust these values without having to dig out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cache.nxp.com/files/microcontrollers/doc/ref_manual/K64P144M120SF5RM.pdf&#34;&gt;datasheet&lt;/a&gt;
and do the math again. Also to possibly automate making the clock configuration code
to prevent me from being the only person who understood how to configure the clocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is someone who loves automation to do? Well, you could solve the equation
directly. However, &lt;a href=&#34;https://endless-turtles.com/&#34;&gt;Michael Abed&lt;/a&gt; introduced me to a program and
library called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Z3Prover/z3&#34;&gt;Z3&lt;/a&gt; which is a constraints solver from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Research&lt;/a&gt; which I found interesting and wanted to do a
simple project with since I thought it might be useful in the future. Also, this
problem is well-suited as it can take a series of equations and constraints and
search the solution space rather trivially easily. Also, it has a way of deciding
if no solution is possible. So I decided
to use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Z3Prover/z3&#34;&gt;Z3&lt;/a&gt; python bindings to create a python library, with a command line
tool and a web API for solving this problem. This is most certainly overkill, but
considering how easily it all went together I would do it again to solve similar
problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cwoodall/k64-pll-calculator&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; and also play with see the resulting
&lt;a href=&#34;http://k64-pll-calculator.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;website and API demo&lt;/a&gt;. But read on for more details!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error Handling: Implementing an Option&lt;T&gt; Type For Embedded C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-10-10-cpp-option/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2016-10-10-cpp-option/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been learning &lt;a href=&#34;http://rust-lang.org&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; lately, which has been an awesome and
rewarding experience thus far. However, at work, and on many of my embedded side
projects I use C/C++ quite extensively. But error handling ends up being
a major pain point and can make an otherwise rather simple API into a disaster.
This can be especially true if you are committed to avoiding throwing exceptions for various
performance and real-time reliability reasons. This is where Rust&amp;rsquo;s model comes
in as a possibly solution (or at the very least an interesting one): the use of
the &lt;code&gt;Result&amp;lt;T, E&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; types and the &lt;code&gt;Option&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; type. For the time being I am going to concentrate on the &lt;code&gt;Option&amp;lt;T&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; type and write about the &lt;code&gt;Result&amp;lt;T, E&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; type in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code for this blog post can be found on github as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cwoodall/cpp-option&#34;&gt;cpp-option&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attaching a Rack To Your Bike with P-Clamps</title>
      <link>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2013-07-07-attach-things-to-your-bike-with-p-clamps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cwoodall.com/posts/2013-07-07-attach-things-to-your-bike-with-p-clamps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A nice and simple hack for attaching things onto bikes without dropping a ton of money.
Before you buy your P-Clamps, or Rubber Coated Metal Clamps, make sure to measure the
diameter of the tube on your bike you want to attach the clamp to. You can get them from
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grainger.com/Grainger/ecatalog/N-1z0dvfc&#34;&gt;Grainger&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mcmaster.com/&#34;&gt;McMaster-Carr&lt;/a&gt;, but they are also easily found in your local
hardware store.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>